-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 优兰达子 笑点滴 水果哥 Mabb 初见 咳嗽的小鱼
校对: 失眠影
诺福克
Koyaanisqatsi.
失衡生活
That music was very foreboding. It's made a shiver go down my spine.
这首歌很诡异 我感觉背上凉飕飕的
- That'll be the air-conditioning.  - I would've taken it off sooner
- 那是因为空调的原因  - 我应该早点关掉
but I was having a fascinating conversation with the proud father
但是我刚才在和一位自豪的父亲聊天
of Norfolk's most sun-tanned child.
他儿子是诺福克晒得最黑的孩子
Just passed his details on to the Social Services.
刚把他的信息给了社会服务部门
The time is 11:59 and 55 seconds.
现在是11点59分55秒
- It's midday.  - Well, no... Well, yeah, it is now.
- 到中午了  - 还没有... 好吧 现在到了
You're listening to Mid-Morning Matters.
您现在正在收听的是"正午特播"节目
Mid-Morning Matters with Alan Partridge.
阿兰・帕屈吉为您带来"正午特播"
Music and chat for the Norfolk generation.
诺福克郡的音乐和谈话节目
Sorry, it's the other way.
对不起 应该是另一边
Later we'll be taking dedications
稍后我们会为
for anyone wrongly turned down for planning permission.
计划许可被错误拒绝的人提出一些建议
Also I'll be asking, which is the worst monger?
我还会问 最赔钱的买卖是什么?
Fish, iron, rumour or war? Pretty clear, that one.
渔业 钢铁 谣言还是战争? 这个问题很清楚
Now it's time for today's large question.
现在到了今天的提问时间
Large question.
提问时间到
It's the near future.
现在是不远的将来
An unprovoked chemical attack from France, or possibly China,
一场莫名其妙的来自法国或者可能是中国的化学袭击
has left us without a sense of smell.
夺走了我们所有的气味
In a whiff-free world, what smell would you miss the most?
在这个没有一点气味的世界 你会最想念什么味道?
- Tom in Diss?  - Petrol.
- 在迪斯的汤姆?  - 汽油味
Nice. Wrongly referred to by the Americans as "gas".
很好 美国人总是错误地叫做"机油"
It's petrol, not gas.
应该是汽油 不是机油
- Dominic in Castle Acre?  - Money.
- 在艾克城堡的多米尼克?  - 钱的味道
Yep. Joe in Holt?
不错 在霍尔特的乔?
- My wife's nightie.  - You kinky get.
- 我老婆的睡衣味  - 你口味真重
- Saucy sod.  - She died, you see.
- 太邪恶了  - 她过世了
- Smells matter.  - They do.
- 确实是气味  - 是的
Hey, Greg.
嗨 格雷格
This is a great station, a real cracker.
这是个不错的电台 高手云集
Yeah. Hi, Pat. Um... this is Jason Tresswell.
是啊 嗨 派特 呃... 这位是杰森・特雷斯维尔
- Managing Director of...  - Goredale Media.
- 总经理 来自于...  - 格尔戴尔传媒公司
Our new owners, huh? I Googled you on Yahoo.
我们的新老板是吗? 我在网络上搜索过你
That's Pat Farrell. Does week nights. 10-12.
这是派特・法莱尔 主持10点到12点的晚间节目
Sleepy-time slot.
睡眠时间段
- So, are you on your way out?  - You tell me.
- 你现在是要出去吗?  - 不如你来告诉我
Is it true you're being taken over by a bunch of corporate whores?
你们公司真的被一群贱人接管了吗?
Er... Gillian, I'm 99% certain that's not true.
呃... 基利安 我99%地确定这不是真的
We've got a text here from Joe in Diss.
我们收到一条来自于迪斯的乔发来的信息
An easy way to solve the problems in Israel...
解决以色列问题一种很简单的方法...
- A thorny issue...  - Would be for Judaism and Islam to merge.
- 一个棘手的问题...  - 犹太教和伊斯兰教合并就好了
Wouldn't hold your breath.
这不太可能
- They both hate pigs.  - True enough.
- 他们都讨厌猪  - 这是真的
You could call it Jislam.
你可以叫它回教
I think you can go in circles, can't you, trying to think of names for something?
我想你试着给什么东西起名字的时候会毫无进展 不是吗?
Even er... a cat.
甚至是... 一只猫
Well, nettles 'cause 'em, dock leaves cure 'em.
荨麻会引发这现象 植物叶子能治愈
It's a sting. It's Sting.
这是讽刺 这是讽刺
- Sorry.  - Never, never criticise Muslims.
- 对不起  - 永远 永远不要评论穆斯林
Only Christians. And Jews a little bit.
只能说基督教 犹太教可以说一些
Alan, it's started. They're here.
阿兰 开始了 他们都到了
We're being taken over.
我们要被接管了
So?
那又怎样?
# Roxanne #
# 罗珊娜 #
# You don't have to put on the red light #
# 你无须再处于红灯区 #
# Those days are over #
# 这种日子已结束 #
# You don't have to sell your body to the night #
# 你不用再出卖身躯于夜中 #
Hello?
有人吗?
Are you in the business centre?
你在工作室吗?
# Coconut, everybody #
# 椰子 大家一起来 #
# Like de coconut #
# 就像椰子一样 #
# Coconut, coconut... #
# 椰子 椰子... #
# Coconut, coconut #
Oh, hello, Lynn. Just reading about how ospreys died out in Britain
你好 琳 我在读关于鱼鹰在英国灭绝的文章
and had to be reintroduced from Scandinavia in the early '90s.
90年代早期又不得不从斯堪的纳维亚引进
Now I think there are almost 500 of them.
我觉得现在大概有500只了
Yeah. 480.
没错 480只
It shows we should treasure and value our wildlife.
它告诉我们应该珍惜野生生物
So, what you got, girl?
你有什么事吗 姑娘?
Well, the butchers want you to do another voiceover.
卖肉的想让你再录一次宣传录音
"Bannan's the Butcher's.
"巴南肉店
Yesterday's meat at today's prices."
不新鲜的肉 不低廉的价格"
You've had the Mayor of Hickling get in touch.
席克林的市长来联系你了
He listens to your show and wants to offer you the freedom of the village.
他听了你的节目 准许你随意出入小镇
- It doesn't even have a post office.  - They give you a big key.
- 那里连邮局都没有  - 他们给了你一把很大的钥匙
- How big?  - That big.
- 多么大?  - 这么大
Tell him I accept.
告诉他我接受了
Everything seems to be chugging along nicely.
看上去事情进行得很顺利
Everything OK, Alan?
一切都好吗 阿兰?
Michael's just sent a text saying he hasn't bought toilet paper in 18 months.
麦克刚刚发了一条短信说 他已经18个月没有买卫生纸了
- How does he...  - He steals it from a pub.
- 他怎么...  - 他从一个酒吧偷的
- Oh.  - That's a relief.
- 哦  - 真是松了一口气
Shared a bag of salty popcorn with him last week.
上周刚和他一起吃过同一包咸爆米花
- # Roll out the barrel! #  - Hi, I'm Pat Farrell.
- # 滚啤酒桶! #  - 大家好 我是派特・法莱尔
Join me tonight at 10 for a hearty casserole of tunes, cheer and chin-wag.
欢迎您10点准时收听由我主持的音乐 励志 情感节目盛宴
Local folk trio Will-o-the-wisp will be playing live in the studio,
演播间里为您现场表演的是民族三重奏"鬼火"乐队
and I'll be taking your calls on my ever popular fireside phone-in.
我会接听您的热线电话
Don't miss it.
不容错过
OK, for those who haven't slipped into a coma,
如果您还没有昏睡过去
you are listening to the Breakfast Show with Danny Sinclair and these muppets.
您将听到的是丹尼・辛克莱尔和他的小伙伴一起为您带来的早间新闻
- How we feeling this morning, guys?  - Better than you, by the look of things.
- 今天早上感觉怎么样 伙计们?  - 看上去比你好
- I had it large. I got on it.  - Take it easy tonight, then.
- 我压力很大 我上电台了  - 那今晚放松些
I would but we've got the launch tonight.
我会的 但是我们今晚有活动
Cause as you know, North Norfolk Digital are changing their name to...
您可能已经知道了 北诺福克数字电台将改名为...
Shape. The Way You Want It To Be.
谢普电台 您想要的电台
# Shape. The Way You Want It To Be #
# 谢普电台 您想要的电台 #
Coming up next, Alan Partridge. God bless him, how old is he?
接下来说说阿兰・帕屈吉 天啊 他多大了?
60 or something. Got to be, hasn't he?
差不多60了吧 一定是 对吗?
55.
只有55
Alan, we love you, mate. We love you really.
阿兰 我们爱你 我们真的爱你
This one's for you if you're listening.
如果你在听节目 这首歌送给你
It's Roachford.
来自于洛奇福德
# Well, I don't pour out my heart like this to everyone #
# 我不是如此真心对待每一个人 #
# Not anyone that I meet #
# 不是我见到的每一个人 #
# And I know it ain't the wine, cos I feel just fine #
# 我知道不是因为酒精 因为我感觉很好 #
# Can't you see, baby? #
# 亲爱的 你看不到吗? #
# I'm still on my feet #
# 我还站在这 #
# Oh, but a cuddly toy #
# 但是一只可爱的玩具 #
# That's my only joy waiting for me when I get home, yeah #
# 那是我回家后唯一剩下的乐趣 #
# And what I need is a girl like you #
# 我只想要像你一样的女孩 #
# All I need, yeah, to call my very own #
# 我想要你属于我 #
# So you gotta feel for me, baby. Feel for me, baby #
# 请你接受我 亲爱的 接受我 宝贝 #
# Yeah, you gotta feel for me, baby. Feel for me, baby #
# Girl, you gotta feel for me, baby. Feel for me, baby #
# 请你接受我 亲爱的 接受我 宝贝 #
# Oh, gimme some love #
# 请爱我一些 #
# Come on, now... #
# 求你... #
Your fog lamps are on.
你的雾灯亮了
Your fog lamps are on. There's no fog.
你的雾灯亮了 现在没有雾
There's no fog.
现在没有雾
No fog.
没有雾
# Oh, a cuddly toy #
# 可爱的玩具 #
# That's my only joy #
# 那是我回家后 #
# Waiting for me when I get home #
# 唯一剩下的乐趣 #
# Na-na #
# 那那 #
# And what I need
# 我只想要 #
# is a girl like you
# 像你一样的女孩 #
# Just to call, call my very own #
# 只要你 只要你属于我 #
# So you gotta feel for me, baby. Feel for me, baby #
# 请你接受我 亲爱的 接受我 宝贝 #
# Yeah, you gotta feel for me, baby. Feel for me, baby #
# You gotta feel for me, baby. Feel for me, baby #
# 请你接受我 亲爱的 接受我 宝贝 #
# Oh, gimme some love #
# 请爱我一些 #
Love that noise.
爱死这声音了
Michael, do it outside.
麦克 到外面去擤鼻涕
- Morning, Michael.  - Morning, Mr. Partridge.
- 早上好 麦克  - 早上好 帕屈吉先生
- Paper.  - I was doing a fist bump.
- 布 赢了  - 我是想和你顶拳
- You would say that now you've lost.  - It's instead of a handshake.
- 你输了当然会这么说  - 只是代替握手
Some people say it's more hygienic than a handshake.
有人说这个比握手更卫生
But who's to say you can't get shit on your fist?
但谁能说你拳头上就没蹭到屎呢?
- Did you hear him making fun of you?  - I did, but as Oscar Wilde said,
- 你听到他开你玩笑了吗?  - 我听到了 但是奥斯卡・王尔德说过
"There's only one thing worse than being talked about."
"在这世上只有一件事比被人议论还要糟糕"
- Cancer.  - No. "Not being talked about."
- 癌症  - 不是 "那就是被忽略"
Oscar Wilde said that's worse than cancer?
奥斯卡・王尔德说这比癌症还要糟糕?
Yeah. I think he was at a party.
是啊 我想他可能在聚会
Probably just being a gay show-off.
可能只是个爱炫耀的基佬
# Shape, Shape, Shape #
# 谢普 谢普 谢普 #
Do you know what I really like? I like waking up
你知道我真正喜欢的是什么吗? 我喜欢
in the morning, breathing in the air and er...
早晨醒来 呼吸着新鲜空气...
actually realising I've made it through the night and I haven't wet the bed.
意识到我熬过了一个晚上 还没有尿床
No, I am joking, obviously, but er...
当然 我是在开玩笑 但是...
they were, of course, very, very dark days indeed.
这些天真的是非常非常难熬
But they're all behind me now.
但是现在都过去了
- Morning, Angela.  - Morning, Alan.
- 早上好 安吉拉  - 早上好 阿兰
Alan Partridge has just walked into the building.
阿兰・帕屈吉刚刚走进大楼
Walking and talking, like The West Wing.
像白宫精英一样边走边话说
- Hope he hasn't hurt himself!  - Mr. President, we have a code red.
- 希望他没有伤到自己!  - 总统先生 有红色警戒
- I've never seen the show.  - No, me neither.
- 我从来没看过那个节目  - 我也没有
Corner coming up.
小心拐角
You never know what's round the corner.
你永远不知道拐个弯后面有什么
More corners, usually.
一般还有更多的拐角
Imagine a world without corners.
想象一下一个没有拐角的世界
No-one would be able to cut any. Everyone would be going round in circles.
没有人能抄近路 大家都只能绕圈
Wow.
哇
I enjoyed that.
我喜欢这样
I will tell you one thing.
告诉你一件事情
When I was going through my bad times,
在我那段困难时期
I found Norfolk was perhaps maybe not the place to be and...
我觉得诺福克可能并不是一个好地方...
just because it's so flat and there was a sort of a...
因为它不景气 而且还有种...
a bleakness about the place, but obviously now...
阴冷的气息 但现在很明显...
You're a good broadcaster, Alan. Don't forget that.
你是一个不错的主播 阿兰 不要忘记这一点
- I wasn't planning to, Pat.  - You seen this memo?
- 我不会忘的 小帕  - 你看到便条了吗?
"Exciting new phase. Here's to the future."
"令人激动的开端 充满希望的未来"
- My days are numbered.  - No-one's getting sacked.
- 我在这里的日子没有几天了  - 没人会被辞退的
It's like Bobby Brushes, the caretaker, when
就像那个管理员鲍比・布拉歇斯
the swimming pool allegations came out.
在游泳馆被指控的时候
- He was in bits.  - Yeah.
- 他惨到家了  - 是啊
It turned out he was just helping those lads towel off. He was being nice.
结果他只是在帮那些小家伙擦干 他在做好事
- He didn't even know them.  - Yeah, but where is he now?
- 他甚至都不认识他们  - 是啊 他现在又在哪里?
- He runs his own business.  - There. He's back on his feet.
- 他在自己做生意  - 看 他又振作起来了
Rents out bouncy castles.
出租充气城堡
For adults, yeah?
是给成人的吧?
- Look at this memo.  - I've seen the memo. It's quite simple.
- 看看这个便条  - 我看到了 很简单
Goredale Media are simply re-imagining our core brand values
格尔戴尔传媒公司重新设想了我们的核心品牌价值
and giving it a name more fitting to multi-platform content delivery.
给它起了一个新名字 方便公司在多平台发展
- They're people people.  - People people sack people.
- 他们都是八面玲珑的人  - 八面玲珑的人解雇别人
No, Pat. People sack people. People people please people.
不是的 小帕 普通人解雇别人 八面玲珑的人取悦别人
- Can you have a word with them, Alan?  - Would you?
- 阿兰 你能帮忙和他们说句话吗?  - 你会吗?
Er... sure. As soon as I can get them all in the same room together.
呃... 当然 只要我能让他们都聚集在一个房间里
- They're all up in the boardroom now.  - That's great.
- 他们现在都在会议室  - 太好了
Thank you. Thank you, Alan. You're a pal.
谢谢 谢谢 阿兰 你真够朋友
Well, pals is pals.
朋友就该仗义
If we're all looking at the last quarterly figures for North Norfolk on page 6.
现在大家在看第六页的北诺福克第四季度数据
Then if you turn to page 5.
接下来请翻到第五页
Hi, guys, don't want to be an agenda-bender, but any chance of a wa-wa?
大家好 我不想耽误大家的日程安排 但是可以给我个机会说两句吗?
- It's not a good time, Alan.  - It's fine, we've time. Come in.
- 阿兰 现在不合适  - 没关系 我们有时间 进来吧
Oh, we moved the other thing. Yeah, it's a good time.
我们调整了另外一件事 好吧 你说吧
Alan. Alan Partridge.
我是阿兰・帕屈吉
Jason Tresswell, MD of Goredale Media.
我是杰森・特雷斯维尔 格尔戴尔传媒公司的总经理
It's not "Alan Alan Partridge". It's "Alan, comma, Alan Partridge".
我不是阿兰・阿兰・帕屈吉 我是阿兰 逗号 阿兰・帕屈吉
I know some people do have two names.
我知道有些人有两个名字
Zsa Zsa Gabor, for instance.
比如莎莎・嘉宝
Duran Duran.
还有杜兰・杜兰乐队
Yeah, that's not as good.
是啊 这个不是很好
Um... Kris Kristofferson.
还有... 克里斯・克里斯托佛森
Excellent small talk. Gentlemen, to business.
不错的开场对话 先生们 我们开始说正事
I am here as one of the more senior D-jocks at this station.
作为台里资深DJ之一
I'm here to talk about jobs.
我来这儿是谈工作的
Like a Nazi officer this, isn't it?
这里就像纳粹一样不是吗?
Should er... snap my heels together.
应该... 立正
- Achtung!  - Guten Tag.
- 稍息!  - 你好
Silence! Sorry. I meant to miss you.
安静! 对不起 我不是故意打中你的
I want you to do something for me.
我希望你们为我做件事
I want you to take all your prejudices, put them in a box marked "prejudices",
我希望你们去除偏见 放到一个叫做"偏见"的盒子里
put it to one side, wipe the prejudice juice off your hands...
放到一边 不要留一点偏见...
Can I just stop you there? Change is healthy, you shouldn't fear it.
我可以打断你吗? 改变是好的 你不应该害怕它
I'm not scared of anything. Not even an elephant,
我什么都不害怕 即使是大象也不害怕
which is interesting, because there's one in this room.
很有意思 现在房间里就有一头
- Wanna know his name?  - Pat Farrell.
- 想知道他的名字吗?  - 派特・法莱尔
It's Pat Farrell. Pat's audience is old.
就是派特・法莱尔 派特的听众都是老年人
Old people, much like dogs, are blindly loyal.
就像狗一样 老年人都有一种盲目的忠实
And if Pat hi-tails it to Cedar FM and they follow,
如果派特跳槽到了希达电台 他们会跟着走
you've got a grey exodus on your hands. A grexodus.
你们将会流失大量的听众 是一次惨重的损失
Hm. That prejudices box doesn't seem quite so cool any more, does it?
偏见的盒子看起来也不那么好看了是吗?
Yeah, but we bought Cedar FM as well.
是的 但我们也买下了希达电台
I didn't know that. I did not know that.
我不知道 我不知道
- The point is...  - You were talking about Pat Farrell.
- 问题是...  - 你刚才在讲派特・法莱尔
Pat Farrell is a great guy.
派特・法莱尔是个不错的人
He's always the first to speak up at union meetings,
开会的时候他总是作为协会成员
being a member of a union.
第一个发言
He's also Irish, which again, weirdly, a plus point, if you like swearing.
他还是一个爱尔兰人 同样很奇怪 如果你喜欢骂人这会是个加分项
"Feckin' dis" and "Feckin' dat".
"去你的这个" "去你的那个"
Some Irish people say "feck off" isn't as bad as "Fuck off"
有些爱尔兰人说"去你的"比"他妈的"好多了
but I think that's bullshit or bellshit.
但我觉得这都是放屁
- The bottom line is, he swears too much.  - This is all very interesting...
- 而且他的脏话太多了  - 这很有趣
I can sum up Pat Farrell in ten words.
我可以用十个字总结派特・法莱尔
Pat isn't very good so let him go, guys, seriously.
派特真的不好 让他走吧
I can condense that to three words.
我可以用三个字概括
Just sack Pat.
解雇他
That completes my presentation.
这就是我的演说
Gentlemen, I'll leave you to your biscuits.
先生们 你们请继续
Gloves.
手套
Oh, fuck.
他妈的
Glove.
还有一只
# Shape #
# 谢普电台 #
# The way you want it to be #
# 您想要的电台 #
Ahh! That was soft rock cocaine enthusiasts, Fleetwood Mac.
啊! 那是弗利特伍德・马克组合的"软岩可卡因爱好者"
And this was Mid-Morning Matters.
您正在收听的是"正午特播"
Where once again,
再强调一遍
- mid-morning... mattered.  - Mattered.
- 正午... 最精彩  - 最精彩
Supposed to do it in sync.
我们应该一起说
- Always leave a gap.  - Sorry.
- 要留一段空白  - 对不起
Simple. Very simple.
很简单 很简单
- You're listening to Shape.  - # The Way You Want It To Be #
- 您现在正在收听的是谢普电台  - # 您想要的电台 #
Mm-hm. Right. And will it take long?
对 会很长时间吗?
It will take long. OK. Hi, Pat. I'll catch you later.
会很长时间 嗨 派特 我一会再去找你
I'm not happy about it, but...
我对此很不高兴 但是...
I'll have to go along with it, won't I?
我只能这样做 不是吗?
The... the problem is that the phone rings even when I'm speaking on it,
问... 问题是我在打着电话的时候手机也会响
so it sounds bloody weird.
很奇怪
In fact, I think it just did it then. Did you hear it? Yes?
其实我觉得刚才又响了 你听到了吗? 是吧?
Yeah. He heard it too.
他也听见了
OK, well, I'll leave it with you.
好 这事就交给你了
Mm-hm. Yep.
嗯 是的
Yep.
是的
All right. Thanks, Susan.
谢谢你 苏珊
If Geoff Susan doesn't mend that phone, there'll be hell to pay.
如果杰夫・苏珊不修那个手机 那就得破财了
They wouldn't even let me say goodbye to my listeners.
他们甚至都不让我对我的听众说声再见
Just gave me 30 minutes to clear out my locker.
只给我三十分钟收拾行李
Well, at least I'm getting their mugs dirty.
至少我弄脏了他们的杯子
Thanks, Alan. You always stuck up for me.
谢谢你 阿兰 你总为难我
Not like the others.
不像别人
Well, I'll let you get back to... Geoff.
你继续和杰夫聊吧
- Who's Geoff?  - Geoff Susan.
- 谁是杰夫?  - 杰夫・苏珊
Oh, yes, of course.
哦 对啊
Ahh...
啊...
I did the right thing, didn't I, Lynn?
我这样做是对的 不是吗 琳?
I mean, I think he knew his days were numbered.
他自己也会料到有这么一天的
More of an assisted suicide really.
这更像是一种安乐死
I just flew him to Switzerland and filled out a few forms and...
我让他飞往瑞士 填几张表 然后...
sloped off to the airport.
从机场溜走
I've got to be honest, Lynn, I'm feeling pretty crummy.
说实话 琳 我感觉糟透了
Pat's Irish, isn't he?
派特是爱尔兰人吗?
To be sure.
当然
Why don't you donate 50 pounds to Sinn Fein?
那你为毛不给新芬党(爱尔兰政党)贡献五十镑呢?
Perfect.
完美
Love that noise.
我喜欢这种声音
Keep me away from the sausage rolls.
因为能使我远离香肠卷
I'm wearing my chubby clothes again.
我又穿回这件既肥又宽的衣服了
- I noticed.  - What the chub, or the clothes?
- 我看到了  - 是说我胖 还是衣服大了?
- Hi, Chub  - My chub.
- 你好 肥肥  - 我是胖了
Not that funny, Lynn.
没那么搞笑吧 琳
- I used to go with prostitutes.  - Brilliant.
- 我以前常找鸡  - 牛叉
Cocaine, that was a trigger. Cocaine, prostitutes.
可卡因是个诱因 可卡因 妓女
Bit of a cycle. Puking up the old er... luminous green bile.
有点像个循环 然后直到把鲜绿的胆汁都吐出来
Yeah, I was withdrawing.
这样 我才离开
I've got my minder with me.
我有保镖
- Lynn?  - She might not seem tough,
- 你是说琳?  - 她看起来不是很结实
but I once saw her stamp on 50 cockroaches in a minute.
但我曾见她一分钟踩死五十只小强
He didn't see. He was in the next room.
他没看见 他那时在隔壁
- It was in Wales.  - It's true, yeah.
- 那是在威尔士的事了  - 但这事是真的
All I could hear was crunch, crunch, crunch, stamp, stamp, stamp.
我只能听见嘎扎嘎扎和咚咚咚的跺脚声
I thought she was country dancing whilst eating cereal.
我还以为她边喝麦片粥边跳乡村舞呢
I thought it was the End of Days. They were legion.
我以为是末日了呢 太多小强了
Lynn likes The Bible.
琳爱读圣经
I've never understood moths.
我无法理解飞蛾
They only come out at night, yet they're attracted to light.
它们只在晚上出来 但又被光所吸引
I don't know why they just don't come out during the day.
我就搞不懂为毛它们不白天出来呢
I've nothing to add to that. If you substituted butterfly...
我不多说了 如果把蝴蝶换成...
Could you go and get me some sausage rolls?
能给我拿点香肠卷吗?
If you substituted butterfly for moth, I think it would sound like poetry, yeah.
如果把飞蛾换成蝴蝶 那就有诗意了
Unfortunately, Wordsworth didn't say:
悲剧地是 沃兹沃斯(英国诗人)没说:
"I wandered lonely as a moth to eat some jumpers in a drawer."
"我似飞蛾天自游 却于抽屉吃跳虫"
"As if that wasn't bad enough, it ate my sock upon the moor."
"倘若那还不够糟 啃我袜子于荒野"
Yeah. It's just... I don't know why a sock could be on the moor.
我也搞不懂荒野里怎会有袜子
A mitten, maybe.
也许是个手套
I actually spewed up some of my stomach lining.
我都吐出我的胃黏膜了
I don't know if you've ever done er... done any horse, have you?
你以前... 吸过海洛因没?
- I've ridden a donkey.  - No, no, no, I mean heroin.
- 我骑过驴  - 我是说海洛因
I know what you mean. No, I've not done heroin.
我知道你的意思 我没吸过
- I don't likes in my films.  - If you can read, read a book.
- 我不喜欢我电影里的标题  - 如果你能读 就读本书吧
Citizen Kane. Black and white. I haven't seen that.
我没看过什么"公民凯恩"或"黑与白"
I tell you what, the best film for me, ever, is still The Godfather.
对我来说 最好的电影一直是"教父"
- Ah, amazing film.  - Perfect film.
- 好电影  - 太完美了
"I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse"
"我将给他开出一个无法拒绝的条件"
- Amazing acting, though.  - Great acting.
- 演得真好  - 演得真好
I tell you what's even better
告诉你什么是更好的
a lot of people are shocked when I say this... the camera angles.
当我说摄影角度时很多人都震惊了
- Alan, I need a word.  - Camera angles?
- 阿兰 过来一下  - 摄影角度?
It's rather delicate.
这件事相当棘手
Remember when you took me for that Christmas meal at the ice rink?
记得你带我去溜冰场吃的那顿圣诞大餐吗?
You remember that woman disinfecting the boots?
记得那个给鞋消毒的女人吗?
The one that took a shine to you.
就是对你一见倾心的那个
I went home and you and her...
我回家了 然后你和她就...
Well, it's... none of my business.
这不关我的事
It is none of your business, but for the record, went back to her place,
虽然不关你的事 但我还是得说 我去了她家
watched Air Crash Investigation, then I fell asleep in her big armchair.
一起看了"空中浩劫" 然后就在大扶手椅上睡着了
A perfectly normal woman.
很普通的一个女人
Well, she's here.
她在那
Lynn, get rid of her. She's a drunk racist.
琳 帮我摆脱他 她是个喝醉的种族歧视者
- I'll tolerate one, but not both.  - Fine.
- 一个我还能受得了 两个我不行啊  - 好吧
But you said I could pop by any time.
你说过我可以随时来的
I know, but my career's hanging by a thread.
我知道 但我的事业命悬一线
- And I'm an embarrassment, am I?  - No, no.
- 我给你丢脸了 对吧?  - 不是 不是
You just wanted sex, you used me.
你只想上我 你利用我
Well, maybe you used me.
也许你利用了我
I... I didn't have much of a say over what went on that night.
我... 我不想说那天晚上发生了什么
Didn't hear you complaining.
没听见你抱怨啊
- I couldn't speak.  - See you round mine again, then.
- 我不能说话啊  - 那待会我家见
I... don't know, I'm... I'm...
我不知道... 我... 我...
- What's wrong with my place?  - Well... all those dogs barking.
- 我家咋了?  - 都是些狗叫声
But it's their bedroom too.
那也是它们的卧室啊
May I have a word?
可以跟你说句话吗?
You're talking clap... crap!
你尽说些废话!
I sound like a fucking Chinky when I'm pissed!
我气爆时像个中国佬!
There we go. All done.
好了 都好了
- What did you say to her?  - I told her that God loves everyone.
- 你给她说啥了?  - 我说上帝爱每一个人
Even sluts.
即使是荡妇
- Good night, Lynn.  - Night, Alan.
- 晚安 琳  - 晚安 阿兰
Hello?
有人吗?
Very funny. Tee-hee.
太有意思了
Very impressive.
很好
Oh, they must have left in a hurry. Something weird's happened.
他们一定是匆忙离开的 有怪事
All right, you freaked me out, so just... pack it...
你们吓到我了 快出来吧...
There you are!
你在这儿!
Pat? Agh!
派特? 啊!
I'm down.
倒了
You...
你...
You step to me?
想害我?
Simon.
赛门
Er...
呃...
Yeah, all right. I'll go on without you.
好吧 我还是继续跑吧
Stop! Stop! Stop!
停车! 停车! 停车!
- I need to commandeer this vehicle.  - What?
- 我来开车  - 什么?
- There's a mad man with a gun.  - Um...
- 有个疯子拿枪追我  - 嗯...
- He's Irish!  - Get in.
- 他是爱尔兰人!  - 上车
Why do you sit so close to the wheel? I could steer with my balls!
你为毛坐得离方向盘这么近? 都能用我的蛋蛋来驾驶了!
- Where's the nearest police station?  - Just here.
- 最近的警局在哪?  - 就在这
Oh... thanks.
谢了
Are you Alan Partrid...?
你是阿兰・帕屈吉吗?
Assault, battery, kidnap, chronic thuggery,
人身侵犯 殴打 绑架 慢性暴行
brandishment, actual bodily harm, grievous bodily harm...
攻击 实际身体伤害 严重人体伤害...
- harm.  - Just stick to what you saw,
- 伤害  - 就说说你所看见的吧
and we'll decide if it's ABH or GBH.
我们会判断是否是实际身体伤害或严重人体伤害
- You mean aitch?  - That's what I said.
- 你是说H?  - 对啊
Nearly, you said haitch.
你貌似刚说的是哈H
"Ha" is the sound of the letter, aitch is its name.
"哈"是这个字母的发音 H是它的名
One is ha, the other is aitch. Neither is "haitch".
一个是哈 一个是H 都不是"哈H"
- I'm sorry, I'm a bit nervous.  - Mr. Partridge?
- 抱歉 我有点紧张  - 帕屈吉先生?
- Something else we need to talk about.  - Oh...
- 我们还有事要谈  - 哦...
- You're not in trouble.  - Oh, fine.
- 你不会有麻烦的  - 好吧
I've never been in a police car before.
我从没坐过警车
May I lower the window, please?
能把车窗摇下来吗?
Foxtrot Sierra. Alpha Papa arriving at the school building.
呼叫狐步山 "阿尔法爸爸"到了
- Officer.  - Mr. Partridge.
- 长官  - 帕屈吉先生
- You were at the police station.  - I was just in the car with you.
- 你刚在警局  - 我就在车上
- If you want to follow me, please.  - Huh.
- 跟我来  - 嗯
- This way, please, sir.  - Yep.
- 这边  - 来了
Let's do it.
开始行动
Mr. Partridge, this is the Gold Commander of the operation.
帕屈吉先生 这是我们这次行动的金牌指挥官
- Seriously, is that what you're called?  - On this operation, yes.
- 你真的被那样称呼?  - 只在这次活动中
I'm Acting Chief Constable Janet Whitehead.
我是代理局长珍妮特・怀特海德
- An honour.  - And I'm Martin Fitch.
- 很荣幸  - 我是马汀・费奇
Send.
发送
From Scotland Yard's Hostage and Crisis Unit.
来自苏格兰场人质危机解救部门
Here to lead the negotiation.
是来管理谈判进程的
Er... little bit awkward. Who's in charge?
不好意思 到底谁是主管啊?
Make no mistake, this lady is in charge.
毫无疑问是这位女士
So here's the situation. Pat is refusing to speak to us directly.
目前的情况就是 派特拒绝和我们直接交谈
He's willing to give us three hostages but only if he can talk to us through you.
但只要他能通过你和我们谈 他愿意放三个人质
Now, we need to know why Pat has done this so
我们要知道派特为什么这样做
we can draw things to a peaceful conclusion.
才能稳定局势
Yeah, sure, I'll talk to him. Deal.
好 我和他谈 没问题
Sorry, wrong person.
抱歉 错了
Come here.
来
OK. Now, are you on any medication?
你有在用药吗?
Er... Just some cream.
我就涂点药膏
I've got very aggressive athlete's foot but that's the only thing about me that is.
我有两只味较重的香港脚 但也就这样
Do you suffer from any nervous conditions, such as panic attacks?
你神经没出过问题吧 比如说恐慌症?
Do I look like I suffer from panic attacks?
我看起来像得恐慌症的人吗?
I've had one panic attack in a car wash.
我在洗车场有过一次恐慌症
It was a perfect storm of no sleep, no wife,
那么大的风暴 睡不着 老婆也不在
and angry brushes whirring towards me.
无情的刷子呼呼地飞向我
By the time the giant hair dryer came on, I was in the footwell.
直到巨型吹风机过来吹时 我还躲在车的脚坑里
Does the idea of weaponry trouble you?
武器会吓到你吗?
Er... no. I've fired several rifles, at fun fairs, and won prizes.
不能... 我在游乐园开过几枪 还赢奖了
But I've never fired one in anger, or at a cat.
但我从没在愤怒中开枪打死一个人或一只猫
We'll have you fully briefed by the tactical firearms team.
我们会给你安排战略武器小组
Cool.
好吧
We'll keep in regular phone contact with you when you go in.
你进去后我们会和你保持电话联系
Very cool. Sorry, go in?
非常好 你是说进去?
- What, into the building?  - Mm-hm.
- 进入大厦?  - 嗯嗯
- To speak to Pat in person?  - Yes, is that not what you...
- 亲自和派特说话?  - 是的 你不是...
- Erm...  - Everything OK?
- 嗯...  - 你没问题吧?
I'm just a little nervous about going into a car wash... er... siege.
要进入洗车场... 进入现场有点紧张
So what do you say, Al? Will you help us?
你怎么想的 阿兰? 你会帮助我们吗?
Yep.
当然
Guys, none of us choose the hand we're dealt...
我们都有选择自己...
- You know...  - We do need an answer, I'm afraid.
- 你知道...  - 我们真心要知道答案
Do you have another siege to go to?
你还有别的案子要处理吗?
It's my understanding that if you say yes, you're allowed a few words.
据我理解 你如果说是的话 就能多说几句
- So you are saying yes?  - I was leaving that to the end.
- 所以你说是?  - 这就是我最后想说的
- If you'd like to come with me.  - Sure.
- 我们一起走吧  - 好的
Can I get a copy of that?
能给我复制一份吗?
- Let's keep this simple, shall we?  - Roger, that.
- 尽量简单化 好吧?  - 明白
- No heroics.  - Ten-four, good buddy.
- 不要说什么豪言壮语  - 明白 好兄弟
Do not physically engage him.
不要和他动手
- Fight a gun, flee a knife, yeah?  - Where do you read that?
- 看到枪反抗 看到刀逃跑 不是吗?  - 你从哪读的?
Big fans of you guys in TFU.
我可是飞行通信部队的超级粉丝
If I had my way, all police officers would carry firearms.
要是我自主行事 所有的警察将会带武器
I think that firearms should remain in the hands of specialists.
我觉得武器应该归还于专家手中
I was going to say that only specialists should be allowed to fire them.
我也正准备说只有专家才能开枪
If you think I've just made that up, you can call my assistant.
如果你认为我是吹的话 那就给我的助理打电话
Alan! Read my lips.
阿兰! 听着
If you jeopardize the safety of any of my men,
一旦由于你没听我的而危及到
or any of those hostages because you've not been listening to me,
我的人或人质的安全
I will take off this police uniform and I will make you pay for it.
我会脱下警服 并让你付出代价的
You want me to buy your police uniform off you?
你想让我买你脱下的那套警服?
No. I'll give you a fucking good hiding, is that clear?
不是 我会让你消失 明白吗?
Yes, that's clear. Yes. That's clear.
明白 太明白了
You're close to me.
你离我太近了
Now, you're a smart bloke, I know you can handle it.
你是个聪明人 我知道你能应对
- I know you won't disappoint me.  - I won't.
- 你不会让我失望的  - 不会的
I aim to please you, and I... I hope to impress you.
我会让你满意的 你会记住我的
- Good man.  - Yeah, you're a good man too.
- 你是好人  - 你也是好人
Right, well, Dom will fill you in.
好 唐会给你强调一些细节的
He has to say all that shit for the insurance.
他又会说什么狗屁保险之类的
- Right.  - Tell me this much, mate.
- 对  - 告诉我
- What's your favourite siege?  - Iranian Embassy.
- 你最喜欢什么样的围攻?  - 伊朗大使馆那样的
Same. Why?
一样 为什么啊?
They used the sound of a pneumatic drill
因为他们利用风钻的声音
to disguise the noise of them removing bricks from a neighbouring wall.
来掩盖他们从隔壁墙上移砖的声音
- So they could smash through and...  - Take them out the game.
- 这样他们就能打通...  - 打败他们
It's just a great siege.
多棒的一次围攻
Right.
好
Do you want to see my gun?
想看看我的枪吗?
Does erm... Yes, please.
想啊
Let's clock the Glock.
看谁能先抢到枪
You'll have to move quicker than that.
你得更快点哦
- Any last messages for your kids?  - Oh... Er...
- 最后想给你孩子说点啥?  - 哦... 嗯...
No, they don't speak to me any more.
没啥说的 他们都不和我说话了
Yeah, "Why don't you speak to me any more?"
你想问"为什么不和我说了?"
I wouldn't know the answer, would I?
我也不知道
So just um... just... tell them I love them.
就告诉他们我爱他们吧
Pat, Alan's coming in now.
派特 阿兰现在就过去
- Greg!  - Oh... Hey, Alan. Thanks.
- 格雷格!  - 哦... 嘿 阿兰 谢谢
- They let you go as well?  - I'm relieved to be getting out of there.
- 他们也让你去了?  - 总算能出来松口气了
- Aren't there still women in there?  - Yeah, well...
- 那还有女人吗?  - 有...
I think it would be a bit sexist to let all the women go out first.
我觉得先让女人出来有点性别歧视
Yeah. Sleep well, Greg.
睡个好觉 格雷格
Thanks.
谢谢
Pat?
派特?
- Prepare to die.  - I'm not ready to!
- 准备受死吧  - 我还没准备好呢!
Alan, it's OK, it's OK, it's me.
阿兰 没事 没事 是我
It's me, Pat.
是我 派特
God, you...
天啊 你...
I just thought a little jokey costume would, you know, put you at ease,
我觉得滑稽点的衣服能让你放松
- give you a giggle.  - Well... mission accomplished.
- 让你笑笑  - 你的目的达成了
Oh, God.
天呐
- It's great to see you.  - Good to see you, too.
- 很高兴见到你  - 我也是
I bought you some cake, not that you deserve it after that.
我给你带了点蛋糕 虽然你不值得有
I should just crush it in my hand. Oh, I already have.
我应该把它捏碎 我已经捏碎了
- How the devil are you?  - Yeah, not bad, not bad.
- 你怎么这么邪恶?  - 还好 还好
How are you feeling?
你感觉怎样?
- Great!  - Good.
- 超爽!  - 好
Oh, er... the police told me to bring you this.
警察让我带来这个
It's just a standard field phone,
是个标准电话
should you feel the inclination to communicate with the authorities.
当你想和当局交流时可以用
Good thing about these things, they're immune to the problems and glitches.
他们对这些问题和小毛病有免疫力
You get with satellite phones.
你可以用卫星电话
But, like I say, it's just an option, really.
但那只是种选择
I just realised, when you asked me now how I was feeling, you meant...
我刚意识到 你问我感觉如何 你的意思是...
Yes, I did.
是的
- Does this answer your question?  - Yes, it does.
- 这个能回答你的问题吗?  - 可以
Oh, hello. Didn't see you there.
嗨 你也在这啊
Someone's been in the wars.
有人奔赴战场了
- That's just Simon.  - Can he breathe through that?
- 是赛门  - 他能呼吸吗?
Of course. It's just like wearing a mask.
当然可以 那只是个面具
At least when someone puts you in a mask, you've got a safe word,
当有人给你戴这样一个面具时 你还能说这只
like "airbag", or "crayfish".
像"安全气囊"或"小龙虾"之类的
What's the er... That thing?
那是什么?
Oh, we made that. It's a head holster.
哦 我们自制的 是个脑袋枪托
- Never heard of one of those.  - Yeah, I'll show you. Simon?
- 以前没见过这玩意儿  - 我示范一下 赛门?
You insert the shotgun.
把枪插进去
- Place on stand. And...  - Walk out.
- 放在支架上 然后...  - 就可以走开
Hands free. I can move around the studio, do anything I want.
就能把手空出来 我就可以为所欲为了
And if something happens... I don't even have to look.
要是情况不妙... 我可以直接爆他的头
Boom. Hit the target.
看都不看 就能正中目标
Yeah... well, you don't need an accomplice.
那么... 看来你也不需要帮手了啊
Well, I've got you now.
你现在在我手上了
Yeah.
好吧
Thank you.
谢谢
So you're with the police now?
你跟警察是一伙的?
Oh, this... no, this is just...
哦 不是这样的...
I think it's Velcro. There you go.
只是个标志 拿掉了
Feck the police.
去他妈的警察
I think they thought that if they did take a pot shot at you
你现在持枪 还劫持了人质
it's a siege, you've got a gun
他们可能是觉得像你开枪的话
that the bullet might pass through you and hit me.
子弹可能会伤到我
Unless they use dum-dums, which explode inside the body.
除非他们用达姆弹 能在体内爆炸成碎片
I said, do not use dum-dums on Pat Ferrell, Farrell, Ferrell.
我对他们说 不要对派特・法莱尔用达姆弹
Just use a high-velocity round that passes through his body
就用高速子弹 会直接穿透身体的那种
because he's a friend of mine.
因为他是我的朋友
And I suppose if I want to shoot you, I can always aim for the head.
如果我想开枪的话 我肯定能打爆你的头
Exactly. Exactly.
没错 没错
Um... I don't even know why I'm wearing it.
呃... 我也不知道为什么会穿它
- So take it off.  - I'll happily take it off.
- 那就脱掉  - 我很愿意脱下来
Go on, then.
那就脱掉
- If you want me to, I'll take it off.  - Fucking take it off!
- 你要是希望我脱掉 那我就脱掉  - 赶快脱掉!
Oh, Pat, now you're making me want to wear it.
派特 你吓得我都不敢脱了
This is not my bag.
不关我的事
I'm... I'm... I'm... a disc jockey.
我... 我... 我就是个电台主播
I'm sorry you got the sack.
很抱歉你被解雇了
I'm 55 years old, I should be at home in bed watching funny videos on YouTube.
可我都55岁了 本应该舒服地窝在家里看搞笑视频
"Sneezing Panda" or "Charlie Bit My Finger".
看"熊猫打喷嚏"或者是"查理咬手指"之类的
Have you seen "Fat woman falls down the hole"?
你看过"肥婆掉洞"吗?
- That's hilarious. Isn't it?  - Yeah.
- 太搞笑了 你觉得呢?  - 没错
I've seen it before, but, yeah.
我以前看过 不过...
That... That should be fenced off really, but erm... I'm glad it wasn't.
那里... 那里应该被围起来的 不过... 围起来就没好戏看了
Great.
真搞笑
Oh, yeah, I'm supposed to ask, where are the hostages?
我想问一下 其他人在哪儿呢?
In there.
在里边
Oh, my God!
天啊!
That's like some son of zoo from Planet Of The Apes.
看起来好像电影"决战猩球"里的动物园
Danny looks a bit... bruised.
丹尼看起来... 挂彩了
I lost my temper a couple of times.
我中间有两次失控了
- Three times.  - Yeah. Yeah, yeah, it was three.
- 三次  - 是啊 他那就是第三次
Go and say hello.
去问个好吧
- Give him a slap yourself, if you want.  - Oh, no...
- 要是你愿意的话 可以和他击个掌  - 不用了...
No, I'll just... I'll just say hello.
我还是... 问个好就行了
- Alan...  - Look, do the police know we're here?
- 阿兰...  - 警察知道我们的位置吗?
Alan! What the hell's going on?
阿兰! 这到底是什么情况?
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
嘿! 安静!
Cool it with the cross-talk, you're professional broadcasters.
别跟讲群口相声似的 你们可是专业播音员
- I'm not, I'm a writer.  - We'll get through this with each other.
- 不 我是作家  - 我们要共度难关
I want everyone to shake hands with everyone else.
大家要相互握手
Now! Whether you want to or not.
愿不愿意都好 马上握手!
This is ridiculous.
太荒谬了
Ow.
哇哦
Hello, er... Connor.
你好... 康纳
- Paper.  - Hi.
- 布 我赢了  - 你好
OK. Pat will not communicate directly with the police.
听好 派特不想跟警察交谈
Only through me.
他只愿意和我交谈
So as of now, I am bullhorn.
现在 我就是传话筒
- But I think we're gonna be OK.  - OK? He hit me!
- 不过大家不会有事的  - 不会有事? 他打我!
Let's not get into who hit who or, you know, who may have deserved it.
别在纠结谁打了谁 或者谁欠打了
You need to keep him away from me. Understand?
别让他靠近我 明白没?
What I need to do, Danny,
丹尼 我要做的是
in conjunction with Jason, is crisis management.
跟杰森一起处理这个紧急状况
I'm sure he'll agree there has been plenty of crisis...
他也一定认为现在危机重重...
- But no management.  - Cowabunga. Walk with me.
- 而且毫无秩序  - 好了 跟着我走
Alan, you do realise you're in the box seat here?
阿兰 你也注意到自己处于有利位置了吧?
You've got the guy's confidence.
他信任你
Yeah. I don't know why.
是啊 我也不知道为什么
I go for a curry with him once a year, and even then I don't have a starter.
我和他每年都会吃一次咖喱饭 尽管我不吃开胃菜
Trouble is, he does.
可是他会
All I need to know is can you handle it?
我只想确定 你能稳住大局吗?
Well, er... put it this way,
这个... 这么说吧
would you ask that of a man who'd gone paint-balling,
你会对一个忘了戴护目镜
realised he'd left his goggles at reception but carried on anyway?
却依然淡定玩彩弹游戏的人问这种问题吗?
- Why?  - You're looking at him.
- 什么意思?  - 那个人就是我
OK, guys, quick wa-wa.
好了 伙计们 再说几句
Just had a pow-wow with Jase, upshot is...
可以和杰森讨论一下 不过...
I'm gonna be his right-hand man on this one.
这次我来当他的右臂
He'll be um... my left-hand man.
他呢... 是我的左膀
- Er...  - Sorry.
- 呃...  - 抱歉
The point is, Pat has not gone mad.
关键是 派特并没疯
He has a grievance. He needs some son of outlet.
他有苦衷 他需要发泄出来
This is Pat Farrell, welcoming you to Roll Out The Farrell on North Norfolk Digital.
大家好 欢迎收听北诺福克电台的"摇滚吧 法莱尔"节目 我是主播派特・法莱尔
OK. Pat may have... may have gone mad.
好吧 派特可能... 可能有点疯了
He may have gone mad.
他可能是疯了
And now we have a text from Cynthia in Holt, who writes,
下面是来自霍尔特的辛西娅的来信 信中写着
Dear Pat, we are sending you a bottle...
亲爱的派特 我们给你寄了一瓶...
- Ma'am, you'd better listen to this.  - Of our homemade plum Brandy.
- 长官 你最好听听这个...  - 自家葡萄干酿造的白兰地
We use it to make Brandy butter...
我们用葡萄干制作白兰地白脱...
- Why am I listening to shit radio?  - That's Pat Farrell, ma'am.
- 广播有什么好听的?  - 长官 是派特・法莱尔在播音
He's broadcasting from the siege.
他在劫持人质的时候播音
Mm, yum, Cynthia. Can't wait.
嗯 辛西娅 我都迫不及待了
Can you gently remind Pat that we had an agreement?
你能否稍微提醒一下派特 我们达成的协议吗?
You are there to communicate with us.
我们是要你去传话的
Listen, I don't know what it says in your police operation manual...
听我说 我不知道警察手册上...
- or in Psycho-babble Weekly.  - Penguin Book of Sieges.
- 或者是心里周刊  - 解救人质教程
Or The Penguin Book of Sieges,
或者解救人质教程是怎么写的
but out here in the field, it's plenty different.
不过今时不同往日
I've got a guy with a gun and a gripe to grind, and he say, "No speaky."
这里有个拿着枪的愤怒的家伙 他不许我说话
I would really like to establish a dialogue here, Alan.
我希望你能让我们建立对话 阿兰
A simple tri-lateral exchange, from Pat, to you, to me, to you, to Pat.
简单的三角对话 派特传话给你 你传话给我 再把我的话传给他
- Do you understand?  - No more interruptions or else!
- 明白吗?  - 别打断我们!
You think I don't have balls? I've got plenty of balls!
你以为我没子弹吗? 子弹多着呢!
I've got balls coming out of my arse!
老子多得是子弹!
- Er... did you hear that?  - Yes.
- 呃... 你听到了吗?  - 听到了
Well, that's... that's the end of the call. Bye.
好吧... 我要挂断电话了 拜拜
You are listening to North Norfolk Digital.
你们正在收听的是北诺福克电台
# Shape.#
# 谢普 #
# The Way You Want It To Be. #
# 您想要的电台 #
# The way you want it to be. #
- Where are all my jingles?  - Jason wanted them deleted.
- 怎么不是我的音乐?  - 杰森把它们删掉了
- He won't have deleted them all.  - He did delete them all.
- 他没全删掉  - 他已经删掉了
- He did delete them all, Pat.  - What?
- 他已经全删掉了 派特  - 什么?
- It was jingle genocide.  - That's not helping, Simon.
- 你的音乐全没了  - 这么做没用的 赛门
The bastard. Alan, take over for me.
混蛋 阿兰 替我一会儿
- No.  - I'm gonna straighten him out.
- 不要啊  - 我要跟他算账
Oh, and... keep it light.
哦 还有... 说些小清新的话题
Right, um... OK.
好吧 呃...
You're listening to the Pat and Alan Show.
你正在收听的是派特和阿兰共同播出的节目
- Mainly Pat.  - You, Jason. Yeah, you.
- 主播是派特  - 杰森 你给我出来
We'll be asking... w... what time...
我们会问... 什么时候...
does Mike Paper slider switch to... to...
麦克・培波将开关...
to mouse his chocolate cups?
调到他的巧克力杯?
- It doesn't make sense.  - It doesn't make sense
- 话说八道什么呢  - 这简直就是胡话
but if you can rearrange to make sense then you could win... bins...
不过要是你重新组织一下 你就会发现... 垃圾箱...
and win...
还会发现...
and windows.
窗户
- Alan, help me!  - So that's our win a bin and window,
- 阿兰 救我!  - 发现垃圾箱还有窗户
re-arrange the sentence, keep it light, competition.
重新组织一下句子 别多想 就是竞争
Oh, shit.
妈的
This is the theme from Ski Sunday.
下面送上"周日滑雪"的主题曲
Sorry for swearing.
抱歉说脏话了
I've put up with shits like you for most of my life...
我已经忍受你这样的混蛋大半辈子了...
One hour.
给你一小时
And if that jingle isn't word for word what I just said,
要是跟我要的音乐有一点差别的话
I am going to shoot you in the feet, then the knees, then the hands.
我要让你的脚 膝盖 手依次尝尝中弹的滋味
And basically anything you've got two of, like your face.
凡是你长了一对的部位都得挨枪 比如你的脸
Oh, yeah. Two-faced.
懂了 两面派
One hour.
只有一个小时
One hour? This is impossible. I'm gonna fucking die.
一个小时? 根本不可能 我要挂了
What are we gonna do?
我们该怎么办?
You can't do a top-quality jingle in an hour.
一个小时根本就做不出来高质量的音律
We can do this. Let me tell you a story, um...
我们可以的 听我讲个故事...
Back in the day, I was MC-ing a conference for Reynard Pharmaceuticals.
以前 我主持过雷纳德医药公司的一个会议
Some of the marketing guys were doing karaoke.
有些市场部的人在唱K
I didn't join in, I tended to shun Japanese culture.
我没加入他们 我有些抵触日本文化
This was the mid-90s, it was more acceptable.
当时是90年代中期 它已经被认可了
But high on a cocktail of champagne and cheap Fosters lager,
但是鸡尾酒 香槟还有啤酒下肚后 我就喝嗨了
I lunged at the microphone.
我对着麦克狂吼
A few minutes later, I was making grown men cry
几分钟后 有几个老人被我演奏的
with my rendition of Summer Of '69 by Bryan Adams.
布莱恩・亚当斯的"69年的夏天"给感动哭了
Thing is, I twisted the lyrics to the Summer Of '29,
关键是 我把歌词改编成了"29年的夏天"
evoking memories of the Wall Street Crash and German hyperintion.
说的是29年华尔街危机和德国紧张局势
- Remember, these guys were in sales.  - Alan, where are you going with this?
- 记住 这些家伙是搞销售的  - 阿兰 你到底要说什么?
The point is, he didn't think he was any good at singing,
他的重点是 他以为自己不擅长唱歌
and it turns out he was quite good.
结果证明他唱歌还是可以的
- Yeah, that.  - And that if you really, really try
- 没错  - 如果拼尽全力的话
- you can do anything.  - And that.
- 一切皆有可能  - 正是如此
I don't care! I'm going to fucking die!
我才不管呢! 老子都要挂了!
Hey, hey, I'm trying to save your head, shoulders, knees and toes.
嘿 我可是在试着拯救你的脑袋 肩膀 膝盖 还有脚趾
- Knees and toes.  - OK, man up, musos.
- 膝盖和脚趾  - 大家快行动起来
- I played synth in a jazz funk band.  - Great, who else?
- 我曾在一个爵士乐队演奏电音  - 太好了 还有谁会的?
I used to be the drummer in Marillion.
我曾经在海狮合唱团当鼓手
Really? There's no time for that.
真的? 没时间纠结这些了
- But wow and great.  - What are you gonna do first?
- 不过还是很惊讶  - 我们从哪儿做起?
I'm gonna lay down a rhythm track.
我去调音轨
Oh.
哦
Lynn Benfield?
琳・本菲尔德在吗?
- I am she.  - Do you know Mr. Alan Partridge?
- 我就是  - 你认识阿兰・帕屈吉先生吗?
OK.
好吧
He wasn't stealing crisps.
他并没有偷拿薯片
He just gets flustered at self-service checkouts
只是他在自助付款时有点发慌
- and takes things without scanning them.  - Miss Benfield...
- 下意识随手拿了东西  - 本菲尔德女士...
He doesn't like being told to put things in bagging areas by automated women.
他不喜欢听机器人的指挥 把东西放在寄存区
No, Miss Benfield, we're here because Mr. Partridge is
你误会了 本菲尔德女士 我来找你是因为
currently involved in an armed siege.
帕屈吉先生卷入了一场持枪劫持案件
- Oh.  - We're informing you as his next of kin.
- 天啊  - 我们通知你 因为你是他的近亲
Take me to him.
带我去见他
# Pat Farrell had a loyal following in #
# 派特・法莱尔忠心耿耿 #
# The local community #
# 对待广播公司 #
# But Goredale Media fucked him over #
# 但格尔戴尔传媒解雇了他 #
# Because they don't care about loyalty #
# 因为他们对忠诚不屑一顾 #
# The only things they give a shit about #
# 他们关心的只有一个 #
# Is the profit margins #
# 就是追逐利润 #
# And if they don't re-instate him #
# 要是他们不重新任用他 #
# He'll take it out on the hostages #
# 他将会对人质下手 #
# Even the ones with kids #
# 不管你是否拖家带口 #
# Better get yourself some body bags #
# 自求多福吧 #
That was beautiful.
真好听
- Could you make me some more?  - Ooh. Er...
- 能再制作长点的吗?  - 哦 呃...
- Definitely!  - Yes, maybe.
- 当然可以!  - 应该可以
Local folk trio Will'o-the-wisp won't be coming in now.
民族三重奏"鬼火"乐队今晚无法演出了
Apparently, there are road closures in Norwich due to a major police...
显然 警察在诺维奇设置了路障...
Thanks for waiting, Miss Benfield.
让你久等了 本菲尔德小姐
We're speaking to anyone who can help us build a picture of Pat Farrell.
我们正尽力了解派特・法莱尔这个人
- You said you know him?  - Ah, well...
- 你认识他吗?  - 算认识吧...
I made three cakes for him over the last year.
去年 我给他做过三个蛋糕
But there was nothing in them that would have led him to do this.
不过蛋糕里没有东西能让他变成现在这样
They were very plain.
那些就是普通的蛋糕
That's not one of our lines of investigation.
我们不是要调查这件事
Just tell us what you know about Pat.
告诉我们你对派特了解多少
Irish. Shock of brown, curly hair.
爱尔兰人 褐色卷发
He's a strong man, with strong arms and a good walk. Moves well.
他很健壮 手臂强壮有力 腿脚也不错
- That's very helpful, Lynn.  - Oh.
- 这些很有帮助 琳  - 是吗
- Thank you.  - Now, how about some coffee?
- 谢啦  - 想来杯咖啡吗?
Oh, of course. How do you take it?
好的 去哪里拿?
No, no, we'll get it for you. Just sit there, I'll be back.
我们给你端过来 你在这里等着就行 我去去就回
Oh...
哦...
I hate all this shit. Telling us how to speak.
我讨厌这些东西 竟然教我们怎样讲话
They think they're giving us an identity but they're...
他们以为能让我们与众不同 但这种做法...
Turning us into nobodies.
只能让我们默默无闻
We're just unit-shifters for the money men.
对于那些只认钱的人 我们就是机器
Sounds quite good.
没错
Alan, did you ever imagine what life would be like in your 50s?
阿兰 你曾经想过50岁以后的生活吗?
I had hopes and dreams. I think we all did.
我曾经有梦想 我想每个人都有
Penny for them.
梦想不值钱
Keep the penny, you've got a gun.
别提钱了 你手里有枪呢
But, yeah, I used to dream that one day I'd drive a brand-new Range Rover
不过 我曾经梦想有一天我开着全新的越野车
towing a speed boat.
拖着快艇跑
I used to dream about growing old with someone I love.
我曾经梦想跟自己爱的人厮守到老
Hm. Both valid.
都不错
It's not gonna happen now, is it?
不会实现了
I miss my Molly so much.
我好想我的茉莉
- Who's this chap?  - That's Molly.
- 这家伙是谁?  - 他就是茉莉
Yes, of course.
没错 当然了
She's got such... brown hair.
她的头发... 颜色真深
A year after that was taken, the angels took her.
拍完这张照片一年后 天使把她带走了
Must have been a few of them.
她一定也是天使
Now I've nobody. No wife.
现在我一无所有 没老婆
No family. No kids.
没家庭 没孩子
I've gotta say, Pat, kids don't make you happy.
不得不说 派特 孩子不会让你开心起来的
Some of the unhappiest times of my life have been with my kids.
我生命中最惨的几次遭遇 都跟我的孩子有关
I remember...
我记得...
a holiday on the beach in Prestatyn.
一次在普里斯坦丁海滨度假
The kids came over to me and said, "Papa, Papa! Follow me."
孩子们跑过来对我说 "爸爸 爸爸! 跟我来"
and... you know...
然后... 你能猜到吧...
I followed them about 200 yards across the sand dunes.
我跟着他们沿着沙丘走了200多码
When I got there, finally, all they'd done was dug a big hole.
等到了才发现 他们只不过是挖了个大坑而已
Miserable.
悲惨经历
Sounds lovely.
挺有爱的
Go-o-o-od morning!
早上好!
Crayfish!
龙虾!
I feel absolutely great.
感觉真爽
There's a lot to be said for a good sleep and a hot shower.
睡个好觉 洗个热水澡感觉真好
Yeah.
是啊
Sleep well, Alan?
睡得好吗 阿兰?
Er... yes, thank you.
呃... 还好 谢了
As the Shape siege enters its first morning,
劫持事件已经过了一天
police are refusing to confirm
警察还是不肯透露
the number or identities of the hostages
被解雇的前主播派特・法莱尔
still being held at gunpoint
持枪劫持的
by sacked DJ, Pat Farrell.
人质的数目和身份
Fellow DJ Alan Partridge
他的同事阿兰・帕屈吉
is in contact with the police
跟警察保持联系
who are now set up at the school behind me.
警察已在我身后的学校里设立指挥所
What would you like us to play, Iris?
你想点播什么歌 埃利斯?
Always On My Mind by Willie Nelson.
威利・纳尔逊的"永远在我心上"
Aw.
好歌
I would love to, Iris, but unfortunately that's not in the system.
我也想为你播这首歌 但不幸的是 这首歌不在系统里
We are only allowed play-approved tracks.
我们只能播允许播出的歌曲
But, Pat, you've got a gun. You can play whatever you like.
但派特 你有枪 你可以放随便什么歌
Leave it with me and I'll see what I can do, OK?
交给我 我来想办法 好吗?
Remember we used to choose our own records?
还记得当年我们自己选要播什么歌吗?
Yeah. Or put on a compilation album if you were tired or couldn't be bothered.
记得 如果嫌麻烦不想挑的时候 就放上张混合版的专辑
Yeah.
是呀
You like country music, Alan?
你喜欢乡村音乐吗 阿兰?
Can't say I do, Pat.
不怎么喜欢 派特
It's just jilted spouses complaining whilst drunk.
那只是被抛弃的苦情人边喝酒边抱怨而已
Also known as a date, if you're over 40.
如果你超过40岁了 那这也算是约会
When a listener asks for a song and I don't have it,
如果听众点的歌我没有
I feel like I've let them down.
我感觉是自己让他们失望了
And Willie Nelson was Molly's favourite too.
威利・纳尔逊也是茉莉的最爱
And Always On My Mind was her favourite song.
"永远在我心上"也正是她最喜欢的歌曲
Do you remember that? The old road show bus.
还记得吗? 这辆路演车
Remember it? I took my family camping in that.
你记得吗? 我带着家里人在里面露营过
- Yeah?  - That was a tough nine days.
- 真的?  - 那九天真是艰难
You see, this bus brought joy to hundreds.
要知道 这辆车给很多人带去过欢乐
I wonder where it is now.
不知道这车现在在哪儿
Probably impounded after it crushed those scouts.
可能在撞过童子军之后 就被送去销毁了吧
No, no, it's in the basement.
不 没有 就停在地下室呢
- Oh?  - Yeah.
- 真的?  - 当然
- Did not know that.  - I used... Oh!
- 我可不知道  - 我过去... 哦!
- Forgot the record. Hold that, will you?  - Sure.
- 忘了拿碟 你帮我拿一下吧?  - 好的
- Give me the gun, Alan.  - Yeah.
- 把枪给我 阿兰  - 考虑下
- The gun, Alan.  - I was looking at my clothes before.
- 把枪给我 阿兰  - 我之前在看自己的衣服
Some people call it gear, don't they? Others call it an outfit.
有些人管这个叫装备 是吧? 有些人还说是造型
But I call it clobber!
但我觉得就是破衣服!
Jesus!
天啊!
Alan! Alan!
阿兰! 阿兰!
Alan! Alan, give me the gun!
阿兰! 阿兰 把枪给我!
- Armed police, stay where you are!  - Give me the gun.
- 武装警察 站着别动!  - 把枪给我
Drop the weapon!
把枪放下!
Alan!
阿兰!
Alan, open the door.
阿兰 快开门
I'm just trying to find some way to escape.
我只是在找逃出去的路
Alan! Alan!
阿兰! 阿兰!
Ayatollah!
冲啊!
He's got a shooter.
他有猎枪
Aargh!
啊!
- You all right, Alan?  - Yeah, I'm fine.
- 你没事吧 阿兰?  - 我没事
Cuddle me, cop!
抱我 警官!
Argh!
啊!
Target down.
目标中枪
Yours, I believe.
我想这是你的
You probably thought I was gay when I gave you that cuddle.
我抱你的时候 你大概会认为我是基佬吧
Don't worry, I'm not.
别担心 我不是
- You're really cool, Alan.  - Yeah, we think you're cool.
- 你真棒 阿兰  - 没错 我们觉得你棒极了
Thank you. Sorry, who are you?
谢谢 抱歉 你们是谁?
Jason Statham.
杰森・斯坦森(著名演员)
Jason Bourne.
杰森・伯恩("谍影重重"主角)
Jason Argonaut.
杰森・阿格诺
- Jason Argonaut?  - Mm.
- 杰森・阿格诺?  - 没错
- It's Jason and the Argonauts.  - Yes.
- 是杰森和阿格诺吧  - 没错
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
You just said, "clobber" and then "Jason and the Argonauts".
你刚说了"破衣服" 然后说了"杰森和阿格诺"
- Oh, sorry.  - All right.
- 抱歉  - 好吧
- We go?  - Yeah.
- 我们走吧?  - 好的
Oh, er... by the way, thanks for not taking the gun.
呃... 顺便说一句 谢谢你没拿枪
Oh... that's fine.
噢... 别客气
You're listening to Pat Farrell. This is Willie Nelson,
我是你们的主播派特・法莱尔 接下来播放威利・纳尔逊的
Always On My Mind.
"永远在我心上"
For someone who's always on my mind, my late wife Molly.
献给我的前妻茉莉 你永远在我心上
# Maybe I didn't love you #
# 也许我对你的爱不够 #
# Quite as often as I could have #
# 常常忽略了你 #
# Maybe I didn't treat you... #
# 也许我待你不够好... #
- Does that man look 59 to you?  - I didn't look.
- 你觉得那照片看着有59岁?  - 我没看
- I just put his name into Google Images.  - This is Pat Farrell.
- 我就谷歌了一下他的名字  - 这才是派特・法莱尔
That is a Pat Farrell. Do I have to do everything?
那是个明星 难道事事都要我亲力亲为?
Ma'am, you better hear this.
长官 你最好听听这个
It's taken from the transcript of the broadcast.
这是他们播音的内容
At 100 hours. Partridge:
第100小时 帕屈吉说:
I wish this was abroad because it would make a brilliant Banged Up Abroad.
这事儿要发生在国外就好了 那简直就是一集精彩的"异域惊魂"
Farrell: What's Banged Up Abroad?
法莱尔说: 什么是"异域惊魂"?
- Partridge: You don't know Banged Up Abroad?  - Farrell: No.
- 帕屈吉说: 你不知道"异域惊魂"?  - 法莱尔说: 不知道
Partridge: Everyone knows Banged Up Abroad.
帕屈吉说: 大家都知道"异域惊魂"
Farrell: I don't. What is Banged Up Abroad?
法莱尔说: 我就不知道 什么是"异域惊魂"?
Partridge: You seriously don't know Banged Up Abroad?
帕屈吉说: 你真的不知道"异域惊魂"?
You have to be shitting me.
肯定是在开玩笑吧
Farrell: I've never even heard of...
法莱尔说: 我从没听说过...
Just get to the bit where they stop saying Banged Up Abroad.
直接跳过他们说"异域惊魂"这段
Sidekick Simon: I once banged up a broad.
助手赛门说: 有一次 我就折断了一块板
Partridge: That's the best you've got, even with a gun to your head?
帕屈吉说: 哪怕有把枪指着你脑袋 你也才想出这么点笑料?
He's got a gun to his head.
他拿枪指着他脑袋
I remember once coming to in a skip in the middle of the afternoon
我记得有次下午我翘班回家 赶过来的时候
with my underpants in my mouth.
嘴里叼着我的内裤
And then I realize, "Oh, these are not my pants!"
然后意识到 "哦 这不是我的裤子!"
Oh, I can laugh about it now but, you know, back then...
我现在倒是能一笑以对了 但当时...
Sssh, ssh. What's that?
轻点 轻点 是什么声音?
Move into position, over.
正在就位 完毕
It's the police.
是警察
If you like canapés that are on the turn, we've hit the motherload.
如果你喜欢自助小电影 那就挖到宝了
Oblong plate, square bowl. Go figure. Whatever happened to circles?
长方形的盘子 方形的碗 自己想想 圆的都去哪儿了?
I mean I've heard of a square meal but that's ridiculous.
虽然我听说过"饱餐一顿"的说法 但太可笑了
I was just saying I've heard of a square meal.
我刚在说我听说过"饱餐一顿"
Alan! Alan! Ssh, ssh.
阿兰! 阿兰! 别说话
OK.
好吧
- We think it's the police.  - Wait.
- 我们觉得是警察  - 等等
- That definitely came from in there.  - That's just a cupboard.
- 肯定是从这里发出的声音  - 只是个柜子
- It's not even an outside wall.  - Careful.
- 连面墙都不算  - 小心点
- No, Jason...  - I'll protect you.
- 别 杰森...  - 我会保护你的
It's not an outside wall. Look, I'll show you. Look.
不是外面的声音 看 我拉开了
- Michael?  - Aye, aye, Mister Partridge.
- 麦克?  - 你好呀 帕屈吉先生
What are you hiding in there for?
你躲在这里面干嘛?
I found myself a place of concealment, like when I was on manoeuvres.
就跟演习的时候一样 我找了块地方藏起来
Take your light off. You're blinding everyone you speak to.
把头灯关了 否则我们都得亮瞎了
- Now it's ?ashing.  - Sorry.
- 变成闪烁灯了  - 抱歉
Michael. You look like some sort of big Geordie Anne Frank.
麦克 你看上去就像大号矿工版的安妮・弗兰克
- How long have you been here?  - All night.
- 你在里面待了多久?  - 一整晚
- What did you eat?  - I had me lunch box.
- 你吃了什么?  - 我带了午餐盒
- Where did you go to the toilet?  - No.
- 那上厕所呢?  - 不是吧
I had me lunch box.
午餐盒呀
Thank God it's got a smoky finish with an airtight seal.
谢天谢地 这盒子总算能锁住那气味
I tell you what. It seals in the freshness.
要我说 这盒子能锁住新鲜
No, Michael. It seals out the freshness.
不 麦克 新鲜的都在盒子外头
What is going on in here?
发生了什么事?
Michael's just visiting us from the cupboard.
麦克刚从柜子出来拜访我们
No need to get shouty-shouty.
不用大呼小叫的
Did those Goredale bastards put you up to this?
是那些格尔戴尔的混蛋让你这么做的吗?
- No.  - No, no. I've been in here a few nights.
- 不  - 没有 我在里面住了好几晚了
- No, one night.  - No, a few nights.
- 不 就一晚  - 不 有好几晚
A few nights this week and the week before.
这星期几晚 上星期也住了几晚
- Why?  - Me brother wanted the bed to himself.
- 为什么?  - 我哥哥想独霸那张床
Ah, yes. Michael suffers from night terrors.
没错 麦克经常做噩梦
He thrashes about like a big salmon.
刚才就像条大三文鱼那样在柜子里扭来扭去
What's in the box?
盒子里是什么?
Er... Michael... Michael let himself down.
呃... 麦克他... 让自己失望了
I'm really sorry. I done a shit in the box.
非常抱歉 我在盒子里拉了坨屎
Well, get rid of it. Throw it out the window.
那快丢掉 从窗户扔出去
Fall back! Fall back!
退后! 退后!
Armed police!
武装警察!
- Identify yourself!  - Identify yourself!
- 报上名来!  - 报上名来!
Alan Partridge. Who the f... Alan Partridge!
阿兰・帕屈吉 真他妈... 我是阿兰・帕屈吉!
You know who I am. I haven't been off the TV that long.
你们都知道我是谁 刚才电视上还播过我呢
- "Identify yourself."  - Alan, it's OK, I'm here. You're safe.
- "报上名来"  - 阿兰 没事了 我来了 你安全了
Yeah, tell them to stop pointing their guns at me.
好吧 让他们别拿枪指着我了
- Lower your weapons.  - Yeah, lower your weapons.
- 放下武器  - 没错 放下武器
Take your hand off your gun. Take your hand off your gun.
把手从枪上拿开 把手从枪上拿开
And the other hand. I can wait here all day.
还有另外一只手 我有的是时间等
Do as he says.
照他说的做
Thank you. Why do you have to turn it into a competition?
谢谢 你们干嘛老要我逼你们呢?
Just because I won. OK.
我总能赢的 好吧
OK. Stop. Pat, stop tugging me.
好了 派特 别扯了
I told you I've got a very sensitive tummy.
我跟你说过 我肚子很敏感的
Who are you talking to, Alan?
你在和谁说话 阿兰?
I've got Pat on the end of the line in both senses.
这根绳子和耳机的那头就是派特
I'm tethered to the building via this rope and relaying messages
这根绳子另一头拴着大楼 而这个艺术级的
from Pat via this state-of-the-art Sennheiser 1,000 head set.
森海塞尔1000耳机另一头的 就是派特
Nice bit of kit. Yeah, I'm telling them that now.
这装备不错的 对 我正在跟他们说呢
If you'd listened, you'd know I'm telling them.
你听着的话 也应该知道我在跟他们说呢
- Pat says "Hi".  - Hi, Pat.
- 派特说"你好"  - 你好 派特
And hi to your fellow officers.
他和所有警官打招呼呢
Hi. Hi, Pat.
你好 派特
Alan, listen. Pat works with us here, this can all end well. OK?
阿兰 听着 只要派特跟我们合作 事情就会完满解决的 好吗?
- I give him my word.  - OK, just... Yep.
- 我保证  - 等等... 好
OK. Pat, you've got to... you're rambling.
好了 派特 你得... 太笼统了
You've got to be more concise. What do you want?
你得说得简洁一点 你要什么?
"I want a helicopter."
"我要直升机"
That's just an example, by the way.
那只是打个比方
Yeah, OK. He wants a helicopter.
好吧 他要直升机
That might not be possible, Alan.
那可能性不大 阿兰
But let's dialogue. What else can we do for him?
但总算是开始交流了 我们还能为他做什么?
Pat says, "Fucking stupid pigs. What the hell's going on?"
派特说 "一帮蠢猪 到底是怎么回事?"
Pat, listen to me. That was not an attack, OK?
派特 听着 那不是突袭 好吗?
We just had to dispose of a box around the corner in a controlled manner.
我们只是用可控制的手段销毁了角落的一个盒子
Pat would prefer it if you spoke through me, as would I.
派特希望你能通过我跟他交谈 我也是
Martin says they deployed a remote RV fitted with a disruptor
马汀说他们刚才用装了干扰器的遥控机器人
to neutralise a suspected IED. He doesn't know
销毁了一个疑似炸弹的东西 他不懂
what you're talking about. He's quite angry.
你在说什么 他很生气
He's honking in my ear like a mad Irish goose.
他正像只生气的爱尔兰鹅一样对我大喊大叫
Aha! We love you, Alan!
啊! 我们爱你 阿兰!
Um... do you mind? It's not a radio road show.
能不能别这样? 现在不是广播台路演
- I'm trying to host a siege here.  - We love you, Alan!
- 我在尝试着解救人质  - 我们爱你 阿兰!
Get away. Who said that?
散了吧 谁说的?
What's it like in there?
里面是什么情况?
Ah... scary, stressful, lots of shouting.
恐怖 紧张 大喊大叫
A bit like being married again.
感觉就像又结婚了一样
And there's a crazy person running around with a gun.
里面有个疯子拿着枪跑来跑去
So it's a lot like being married again.
所以更像又结婚了的样子
And er... when I saw a guy with a shotgun in his mouth begging for mercy then...
如果... 等我看到一个家伙把枪塞嘴里 乞求宽恕的时候
you're ahead of me.
那你们都超前了
You're ahead of me. A lot of you are.
你们好多人都超前了
He's still got his hand on his gun. He thinks I don't know. Yeah, you.
他还把手放在枪上呢 他以为我不知道 说的就是你
- I'm looking at you. Peripheral vision.  - Alan.
- 我在用间接视力看着你呢  - 阿兰
I'm not retreating, Pat's tugging me off.
我不是在撤退 是派特要把我拉回去了
No, come on.
别笑了
- We're better than that. Guys, seriously.  - Alan, wait!
- 说真的 大家被这么幼稚了  - 阿兰 等等!
By the way, there's an extra hostage. Meant to tell you that.
顺便说一句 多了个人质 本该告诉你们的
In a surprise development, DJ Alan Partridge
事件发生惊人发展 主播阿兰・帕屈吉
appeared outside the building, while tethered to a rope.
出现在广播电台 腰上系着根绳子
Footage of his address is already one of the most viewed Youtube videos
这段视频已经一跃成为继"肥婆掉洞"之后
since "Fat Woman Falls Down Hole".
Youtube上点击量最大的视频之一
Mr. Partridge, whose Facebook page
帕屈吉先生的脸书主页上
lists one of his interests as hand-to-hand combat,
写着他的兴趣之一就是徒手格斗
has been acting as mediator between police and the hostage-taker, Pat Farrell.
而他现在也充当着警方和劫匪派特・法莱尔间的沟通中间人
As people around the world ask, who is Alan Partridge?
可能其他国家的人会问 阿兰・帕屈吉是谁?
That was a majestic voice.
那可是重磅发言
You can keep Jesus. As far as I'm concerned,
可以保留耶稣 但在我看来
Neil Diamond will always be King of the Jews.
尼尔・戴蒙德永远是犹太人之王
You are listening to...
您正在收听的是...
# The Partridge and the Poacher #
# 帕屈吉和偷猎者 #
And, what I believe is a world first, I, Alan Partridge, a hostage,
我相信这是世界首例 我 阿兰・帕屈吉 一个人质
broadcasting live from a siege at gunpoint.
正被枪指着进行直播
Pure class, Alan.
真有格调 阿兰
And today, we'll be asking, what was better in the olden days?
今天我们要问的问题是 有什么好东西一去不复返?
OK, Pat, shoot. I mean, you know, start speaking.
派特 开枪吧 我是说 你可以开始了
- Terry in Necton.  - Egypt.
- 尼克顿的特里  - 埃及
- I'm liking this.  - They used to build the pyramids,
- 这个不错  - 他们原来还能造金字塔的
now they can't get you a taxi to the airport.
现在却连送你去机场的出租车都没有
Terry, I like the way you think. Please call again.
特里 我喜欢你的思考方式 要再打来哦
- Will do.  - Nicholas in Weybourne.
- 没问题  - 韦伯恩的尼古拉斯
- Nurses were better in the old days.  - Bull's-eye.
- 以前的护士更好  - 一针见血
They used to be these Florence Nightingale type figures.
原先都是弗洛伦斯・南丁格尔的翻版
These days it's just, you know, short-haired women in trousers
现在都变成了穿着裤子的短发女人
washing their own hands at a sink.
自顾自洗手
Later on, I'll be asking which vegetable has the greatest torsional strength...
稍后我将会问 哪种水果扭力最强...
ie, which can withstand the greatest twisting load before rupture?
也就是说 哪种水果在断裂前 能扭动幅度最大?
- Caroline in Sprowston.  - Beards were better in the olden days.
- 斯布朗斯顿的卡洛琳  - 以前的胡子更好些
- Love it.  - Sebastian in Holt.
- 大爱  - 霍尔特的塞巴斯蒂安
- UK manufacturing.  - Good. Good, but dull.
- 英国制造  - 没错 不过有些钝
- Paul in East Runton.  - Kill 'em all, Pat.
- 东郎顿的保罗  - 杀光他们 帕特
Shoot the women first.
先杀女人
We'll also be asking, have you ever met a genuinely clever bus driver?
我们还要问 你遇到过真正聪明的公交车司机吗?
I wonder what the listening figures are for this.
我在想现在的收听率得有多高
Yeah. Can you stop drumming?
是啊 你能别再敲了吗?
OK. Time for fact of the day.
好了 又到了"今日真相"时间
Fact of the day. Sponsored by Norfolk Dairies.
今日真相 由诺福克乳业赞助播出
- Cows don't have hymens.  - Absolutely correct.
- 奶牛没有处女膜  - 完全正确
Cows do not have hymens, just a partially opened cervix.
奶牛的确没有处女膜 只有半开的阴道
The time is 10:22.
现在的时间是10点22分
Right now, to your muster stations. It's Bryan Ferry.
下面将要播放的是布莱恩・费瑞的歌曲
Ah... that was... that was er...
刚才... 刚才那段...
- Very good.  - Yeah. Radio gravy.
- 很好  - 没错 很不错
Wow.
真棒
I suppose you forget about the gun after a while, don't you?
我想过了这么会儿 你肯定忘了那把枪了吧?
- No, I don't.  - OK.
- 不 没有  - 好吧
Good.
很好
Lynn! Lynn Benfield, can we have a word?
琳! 琳・本菲尔德 我们能谈谈吗?
Oh, Alan doesn't like me speaking to the press.
阿兰不喜欢我跟媒体交流
- We're not press. We're television.  - Well, I'm... I'm not really...
- 我们不是媒体 是电视台  - 我... 真的不想...
We've got hair and make-up.
我们有发型师和化妆师
Oh!
不错!
Back now to Norwich where DJ Alan Partridge
我们将视线回到诺维奇 主播阿兰・帕屈吉
- continues to bring news of the radio...  - Ah, Angela?
- 持续通过电波传递...  - 安吉拉?
- Someone wants a word with you.  - Who?
- 有人想和你聊聊  - 谁?
Him.
他
Tensions on the Korean peninsula continue...
朝鲜半岛的紧张局势在持续...
- Why?  - Following Kim Jong-il...
- 为什么?  - 金正夜...
Oh... shit.
哦... 该死
Vegas, I was doing kind of...
在拉斯维加斯 我在...
For anyone's price range...
适合大众的价格...
Mounting tensions in North...
北部的紧张局势...
Erectile dysfunction...
勃起功能障碍...
- Inside, Partridge seems unfazed...  - Ah, him.
- 帕屈吉在里面似乎一点都不苦恼...  - 是他
- Me on TV. Good photo.  - He tried instead
- 我上电视了 照片不错  - 他和持枪男子
to calm the gunman by joining him in the studio.
一起主播 试图安抚他的情绪
Yes, just your basic disabled loo.
好了 就是个标准的残疾人卫生间
You've got your lowered seat pan, back pad, high-vis grab bar, panic cord, lady bin.
低位坐便器 靠背 扶手 紧急按钮 还有丢卫生巾的桶
Alan, calm down. You're being all hectic.
阿兰 淡定点 你太兴奋了
This is because you're on TV, isn't it? You're all puffed up like a Robin.
就因为你上了电视吗? 你一直叽叽喳喳说个不停
It's like you can see in me.
你就是这么看我的
Alan, you didn't bring me in here to talk about disabled toilet facilities, did you?
阿兰 你叫我来这 不只是让我看残疾人卫生间的吧?
Yeah, I did. No, I didn't.
是的 不 不是
Oh, wow. Lynn, you look fantastic.
哇 琳 你好美啊
Good gracious.
天啊
I'm sorry about the nasal whistle. It's when I'm anxious.
不好意思 我鼻子叫了 一紧张我就这样
You know... you know, "Shape... the way you want it to be"?
你听过吗... "谢普... 您想要的电台"?
- Yeah?  - Your shape's the way I want it to be.
- 怎么了?  - 我觉得你身材刚刚好
I'm on about your body.
我都性奋了
- What might this be?  - That... is my damned todger.
- 这是什么?  - 是... 我的小伙伴
And it's all the fault of a certain Miss Angela...
这都是安吉拉小姐闯的祸...
I'm sorry, I don't know your second name.
不好意思 我不知道你姓什么
He's very brave. He was once feeding ducks in the park.
他很勇敢 有一次他在公园喂鸭子
One took a peck at him and instead of retreating,
一只鸭子没吃食 而是咬了他一口
he hit it with the back of his hand.
他就用手背打了它一下
- DJ Alan Partridge...  - Hi. You got time for a quick wah-wah?
- 主播阿兰・帕屈吉...  - 嗨 你还有空"哇哇"一下吗?
- What?  - Quick wah-wah.
- 什么意思?  - 哇哇
- Oh, you mean "wa-wa"?  - Yeah. Yeah.
- 你指的是聊几句?  - 是的
- Sorry. You just did a different noise.  - Sorry.
- 刚刚你学得不太像  - 不好意思
Look... how are you feeling about this whole media circus? How you feeling?
这些... 这些媒体的把戏 你怎么看?
Between you and me, pretty puffed up.
他们在虚张声势
- Like an owl.  - Let's hope you're a wise one.
- 就像猫头鹰那样  - 希望你是个聪明人
Nice. I pitched it up, you knocked it out of the park.
太好了 我投掷 你击球
Synergy. Oh, no, that's lesbians.
我们联手 不 这是女同的手势
Let me tell you something, Alan.
实话跟你说吧 阿兰
As far as the press is concerned, you are the face of this siege.
这次劫持事件中 你是媒体注意力的焦点
- I am siege face.  - Exactly.
- 我是焦点  - 没错
After this, you'll get more offers than a whore at our Christmas party.
这件事之后 你找工作比圣诞脱衣舞娘都容易
I like that. Yeah, I like that.
我喜欢 嗯 我喜欢
- Yeah.  - Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 嗯  - 哦 没错 没错
You'd know a thing or two about that, wouldn't you?
你知道点什么 是吧?
That would be... "Mm-hm. Hmm," he says. That's a moustache.
这时应该... "嗯" 他说 然后挠挠胡子
Seriously, did you give her one?
说真的 你上过她吗?
Well, I... I gave her a ruddy big kiss she won't forget in a hurry.
哦... 我只是迫不及待地吻了她
Hand on the outside of the bra. Er... you know, reconnaissance.
刚想解开胸罩 呃... 观望一下
And then I just held her in my arms because she
然后她躺在我怀里
told me she never knew her mother, and I said,
她说从没见过她妈妈
"Well, my mother raised me and lived to a ripe old age.
我说 "我是我妈带大的 她活了很大年纪
But guess what? I never really knew her."
但知道吗? 我一点也不了解她"
Erm... and...
呃... 然后...
to get back on track, erm...
接着刚才的说 呃...
Yeah, I mean... yeah, whoo!
我是说... 好棒!
- I like you.  - I like you.
- 我很喜欢你  - 我也喜欢你
He likes me, Lynn. Jason Tresswell likes me.
琳 他喜欢我 杰森・特雷斯维尔喜欢我
- Alan? Are you OK?  - I've got to be quick.
- 阿兰? 你还好吧?  - 我长话短说
Pat thinks I've borrowed his phone to play Angry Birds.
派特以为我借他手机玩愤怒的小鸟
- Of course. What is it?  - A computerised bird-throwing game.
- 好吧 那是什么?  - 那是扔小鸟的电子游戏
- No, I meant...  - I'm joking, Lynn.
- 不 我是问...  - 我开玩笑的 琳
Enjoy me. Everyone else is.
给点面子嘛 大家都很给我面子
Goredale Media think I'm some sort of Christ 2.0.
格尔戴尔传媒公司觉得我是上帝二代
Do you know, I'm within a brair's headth of getting the breakfast show.
知道吗 我马上就要去录早间新闻了
I'll call myself the Morning Rooster, or the Talking Cock.
我是个打鸣的公鸡
- Alan, you're not thinking clearly.  - Yes, I am.
- 阿兰 你思维混乱了  - 我想好了
Lynn, I'll say this once and I'll say it again.
琳 我再说一遍
My career's getting a shot in the arm and if I can stay in here to the bitter end,
只要熬过了这一关 我的事业就会飞黄腾达的
I will be the biggest thing to come out of Norwich since... Lord Nelson or Trisha.
我会是继纳尔逊勋爵和特丽莎修女之后的又一位伟人...
Think about that and what that means.
想想这意味什么吧
Your first priority is the welfare of the hostages.
你的首要任务是确保人质安全
That's good. Put that out as a press release and say I said it.
没错 告诉媒体这句话是我说的
Alan, your ego's getting the better of you.
阿兰 你越来越妄自尊大了
I've just got to stay alert and focused. I'm playing them like an oboe, Lynn.
我只需保持警觉 我把他们耍得团团转 琳
How effed up is that?
是不是很厉害?
火灾出口 禁止堆放物品
- Alan? Alan?  - Oh...
- 阿兰? 阿兰?  - 哦...
Ohh! Christ's sake.
哦! 天啊
Not now. Oh, God.
别这样 哦 天啊
I'm caught on the latch.
我被插销卡主了
Oh, come on. Please.
别这样 求你了
Stop, armed police! Get your hands above your head.
不准动 警察 举起手来!
- I've just got...  - Get your hands above your head!
- 我只是...  - 把手举起来!
- I want to get those trousers.  - Do it! Hands above your head.
- 我想把裤子拿下来  - 立刻把手举起来!
- They're my trousers.  - Get your hands above your head now!
- 这是我的裤子  - 立刻把手举起来!
What are you doing? It's weird.
你在干什么? 那么奇怪
There are paparazzi all over the place
这地方到处都是狗仔队
and I do not want them to get a photograph of my genitals.
我可不想让他们拍到我的小鸡鸡
- Oh, come on!  - That's it, look at me.
- 不会吧!  - 很好 来张正脸的
And how were the hostages when you left?
你离开的时候人质的情况如何?
- Crouched.  - I mean, what's their state of mind?
- 瑟瑟发抖  - 他们的精神状态怎么样?
Oh. Er... If I'm honest, a bit moany. Yeah. Is someone writing this down?
哦... 说实话 他们不停抱怨 没人要记下来吗?
- Yeah.  - Sorry. I thought you were some clothes.
- 我在记  - 不好意思 我还以为你是头儿呢
Thanks for the forensic trousers, by the way.
差点忘了 谢谢给我尸检用的裤子
- Could you just um...?  - Crikey. Yeah, sorry.
- 你可不可以...?  - 哦 不好意思
I was actually going to fashion a sort of make-shift modesty sporran
我只是想用这俩没用的袖子
from the vacant arm flaps.
弄点时尚元素
OK, I think we're done here.
好了 我们问完了
Any chance of freshening up? I just need to wipe my face with a big hot towel.
我可不可以梳洗一下? 我想用热毛巾擦把脸
Presumably you wanna use me as part of your media strat?
你们打算让我在新闻发布会上出镜吗?
No.
不用
- Do you agree?  - 100 per cent.
- 你同意吗?  - 完全同意
Gotcha.
我懂了
The police said you could do media interviews when the siege is over.
警察说人质被解救之后你就可以接受采访了
It will be too late then, Lynn. People move on.
那就太晚了 琳 人们很快就会忘了
Goredale Media will move on.
格尔戴尔传媒公司也会重新开始
But you're still being talked about.
但大家还是会谈论你
Only cos every time I look at the telly, they're showing a picture of my arse.
他们谈论我只是因为我光着屁股
It's all right for you. Every other time I look, they show a picture of your face.
对你来说没什么 电视上只放过你的脸
And then the next time... surprise, surprise, my arse again.
但是一不小心... 就又亮出了我的屁股
I was only telling people about you.
我只是跟媒体聊了些你的事
You know, I was Goredale's golden goose, and now I'm just Partridge pie, with peas.
过去我是格尔戴尔的财神爷 但现在却是个帕屈吉馅饼 上面还有豌豆
But why do you want to work for people like that?
但你为什么想要为那样的人卖命?
- Goredale are bullies.  - Yeah. And what do you do with a bully?
- 格尔戴尔欺软怕硬  - 是 但那又怎么样?
You make friends with the bully so they bully someone else.
只能和他们做朋友 让他们别欺负自己
- "What doth it profit a man..."  - DOTH?
- "如果失去了灵魂..."  - 海牙宣言?
"if he gains the whole world yet loses his soul?" Matthew, chapter eight...
"就算赢了全世界 又有什么意义呢?" 马太福音 第八章...
Yeah, I know who wrote it. I'm not going to sell my soul, Lynn.
我知道谁写的 我不会出卖自己的灵魂的 琳
I want to, if you like, lend my soul to Goredale Media
我想出长期出租我的灵魂 给格尔戴尔传媒公司
on a long-term basis for cash.
能换好多钱
It's a very different thing.
这可不是一回事
I don't know how you can look yourself in the eye.
我不知道你是怎么看待你自己的
I can't, Lynn. My nose is in the way.
我看不到自己 琳 鼻子太高了
You can talk, prattling away on every news bulletin.
你可以对报道妄加评论
I mean, who the heck do you think you are?
但你是哪颗葱啊?
- I'm Lynn Benfield.  - You don't look like Lynn Benfield.
- 我是琳・本菲尔德  - 你看起来不像琳・本菲尔德
I mean, what has happened to you, with your attitude and your hair?
你的头发 还有你的态度 都是怎么回事?
You've literally become a big head.
你变成一个大头娃娃
- I like it.  - I take no pleasure in saying this, Lynn,
- 我很喜欢  - 我也不想这么说 琳
but a lot of people think it looks like a photograph of an explosion.
但你的脑袋看起来就像正在爆炸的蘑菇云
I don't know if I want to work for a man like you.
我不想再和你这样的人共事了
I don't know that I want to employ someone who looks like a madam.
我也不想雇佣一个看起来像大妈的人
And I don't mean a Parisian one
我指的可不是巴黎的时尚大妈
I mean, one who lives in a terraced house behind a train station.
我指的是那种住在铁道旁小破屋里的大妈
- Doors opening!  - Armed police! Armed police!
- 把门打开!  - 武装警察!
Oh, shut up, will you? Stop shouting.
闭嘴 别嚷嚷了
- Easy, Pat. Mind the steps.  - I'm able to walk down steps, all right?
- 别激动 派特 小心脚下  - 我会下楼梯的 明白吗?
He means because the gun's against my head.
他这么说是因为你正用枪指着我的脑袋
- Everybody has an opinion, huh?  - Hear, hear. Well said.
- 每个人都自己的想法 是吧?  - 听到了 继续说
- Oh.  - Hi, Pat.
- 哦  - 嗨 派特
Hey, Alan. What happened? We were in the middle of a show,
嘿 阿兰 怎么回事? 我们正在演出一场伟大的节目
and then your arse is all over the Internet.
可突然你的屁股出现在了网上
Looked like you had a Turkey's head between your legs.
你两腿之间的那个是火鸡头吧
No, it didn't. No, it didn't. It doesn't have a beak.
不是 不是 他们有鸡喙
And, yeah, I took an executive decision
而且我很明智地
to stow my cock and balls up against my backside.
把小鸡鸡夹在了屁股里
I can't believe you left me with this nutcase.
真不敢相信 你把我丢给了这群疯子
Hang on a minute, you're the one with the gun.
等一下 你也有枪
- See? He's hilarious.  - He's solid. He's solid.
- 看到了吗? 他还挺逗的  - 他不紧张了
- Pizzas coming through now, Pat.  - Hey. Hey, hey. Hold on. Helmet off.
- 送披萨的 派特  - 嘿 嘿 站住 把头盔拿下来
Oh, hello.
哦 你好
Actually, I want Alan to bring them in.
我想让阿兰给我送来
That might not be possible, Pat. Alan's not prepared to do that.
派特 那样不行的 阿兰没准备好
No... I am prepared to do that.
不... 我准备好了
- It's not that simple. Pat.  - Do you want me to release some people?
- 没这么简单 派特  - 你想让我放几个人?
Sure. Let's talk about that.
是的 我们商量一下
Alan, what do you reckon if I let the women go?
阿兰 我先放了女人 你看怎么样?
Yeah, let a couple of the women go. Maybe keep Angela.
嗯 放了那几个女人 先留着安吉拉
- But her kids will be worried sick.  - She's got kids?
- 但她的孩子们肯定很想她  - 她都有孩子了?
Yeah. Two boys, 14 and 15.
嗯 两个儿子 一个14岁一个15岁
I believe they're a real handful.
肯定很忙
Yeah, what was I thinking? Let all the women go.
我在想什么呢? 放了所有的女人吧
Pat, just give me five minutes with head office.
派特 给我五分钟的时间联系一下总部
He's bringing them in now. Alan, come on.
他来送披萨 阿兰 快过来
- Top one.  - Top one.
- 最上面那盒  - 最上面那盒
- Yeah, yeah, cheers, guys. Top one.  - OK, come on, son.
- 哦 哦 好的 最上面那盒  - 好了 过来
Oh, shit.
糟了
Why did you say hello to that delivery guy?
你为什么要和送餐员打招呼?
Oh, him? No, he just reminded me of a man I know called Mike Cable,
他? 他让我想起来一个老相识 麦克・凯布
who did my accounts from '97 to '98.
他帮我报税 从97年到98年
Actually, no. '99.
不 到99年
Till he stopped because his daughter was very ill.
但后来他女儿生了重病
Yeah, it was touch and go, actually.
看到他让我想起来从前
He and Sandra were in bits, they had to cancel their holiday.
他和桑德拉花掉了所有积蓄 也不能去度假
- It was a fly-drive to Tuscany.  - Hm.
- 他们本想乘飞机去托斯卡纳区(意大利地名)  - 嗯
I must tell him, actually, that there's a policeman that looks just like him.
下次见到他一定要告诉他 有个警察长得和他很像
What's that?
你说什么?
Must tell Mike that there's a pizza man who looks just like him.
我要告诉麦克有个送披萨的长得和他很像
I'm famished.
我要饿死了
- Ladies, you're free to go.  - What?
- 女士们 你们可以走了  - 真的吗?
- Yep.  - God bless you, Pat.
- 是的  - 上帝保佑你 派特
See you. Bye.
回头见
I'll make you a home-made pizza when you get out.
等出去我会亲手给你做披萨吃
Yeah, these pizzas are pretty good.
嗯 这家的披萨很不错
- Cinderella.  - Yeah, well...
- 灰姑娘的鞋子  - 嗯...
No, hers was... that was a glass one, wasn't it?
不 她穿的... 是水晶鞋 是吧?
Here comes the Tin Man.
铁皮人来了
- Just trying to find your pizza.  - Well, just give me that one.
- 我正要给你拿一份披萨  - 给我那份就可以
- Hm?  - That one.
- 嗯?  - 那个
- Which one?  - The top one.
- 哪个?  - 第一个
Oh...
哦...
- I'll take the pizzas.  - Oh, yeah. Yeah.
- 我去分披萨  - 哦 好的
Woo-ho, stuffed crust! Thanks for coming back, Alan.
哇 纸盒披萨! 谢谢你又回来了 阿兰
- What are you doing?  - I'm just seeing how you'll look
- 你在干嘛?  - 我只是想看看
on the billboard for when you start on The Breakfast Show.
当你在大屏幕上播报早间新闻的样子
- The Breakfast Show?  - Alan, can I have a word?
- 早间新闻?  - 阿兰 能和你聊聊吗?
Yeah, sure. Just bringing the pizza cutter.
当然能 我正好拿了切披萨的刀
Right, how many do you want. Six or eight?
你想要分成几份 六份还是八份?
Oh, my God, that's a taser!
天啊 有把电枪!
This is no use, it's a pizza cutter. And that is not a pizza.
没有用啊 我拿着披萨刀 这里却没有披萨
Thing is, how did it get there? Erm...
但它怎么会在这里呢? 呃...
Unless the pizza company are running a competition in which you win a taser.
有可能是披萨店正在举办活动 你中了一把枪
That doesn't make sense, does it? Do you realise, it's the police?
但这说不通 是吧? 你发现了吗 有可能是警察放的?
The ruddy po... do you know... they've got some brass neck for a bunch of coppers.
那些警察... 他们有铜制的护颈
I'm actually really angry about that.
对此我很气愤
You should keep that as an extra weapon.
你应该留着这把枪
What kind of fool do you take me for, eh? I'm one step ahead of all of you.
你以为我是笨蛋吗? 我早都看穿了你们的把戏
And I'm just a step behind you, mate.
我也看穿你了 哥们
- Ooh.  - Never take your eye off the ball, Pat.
- 哦  - 要一直盯着目标 派特
First rule of business.
这是获胜的第一条准则
Second rule of business, always be prepared for an opportunity
第二条准则 时刻准备好抓住机会
when it arises, like I was just then.
就像我这样
Yeah.
是的
Of course I wouldn't expect you to understand that. It's Darwinian.
我知道这对你来说有点高深 这是达尔文的进化论
- You're a runt.  - Is that what you think, Alan?
- 你这个畜生  - 你也这么想吗 阿兰?
I wouldn't quite, you know, use those words.
我不会说那些脏字的
Well, I think... I think...
但是... 我想...
the sort of the gist of what, you know...
他们的意思表达的是对的...
I just don't like bullies.
我只是不想被欺负
- Um... can I take this off, please?  - Oh, yeah. Yeah, sure.
- 嗯... 我能把这个脱掉吗?  - 哦 当然可以
- No, I'm talking to him.  - Oh, for fuck's sake.
- 不 我在跟他说话  - 哦 该死的
- Yeah, go ahead.  - Thank you.
- 脱吧  - 谢谢
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
Well, I was worried about the old head but I think I've got a handle on it.
我有点担心自己撑不撑得住 但应该没事
- Very witty.  - Alan's a smart cookie, Pat.
- 很好  - 阿兰很机智的 帕特
He's treated this whole crisis like a business opportunity.
他想从这件危机中牟取商业利益
He's taken a look around him and he's thought, "How can I make this work for me?"
他打量着四周 心想"我该怎么利用这一切呢?"
- Well done, Alan.  - Cheers.
- 做得好 阿兰  - 谢谢
- Yeah, well done, Alan.  - Thank you.
- 没错 做得好 阿兰  - 谢谢
You know, you and me, we've got something going here.
知道吗 你和我有很多相似之处
Pat might be a dinosaur, filling his show
派特是个老古板 只会想1983年那样
with chit-chat and phone-ins like it's 1983,
在节目里聊天和接观众电话
but you're one of us.
但你和我们一样
You know radio's just business. You'll do well out of this.
你知道媒体是用来赚钱的 你很聪明
And er... I'll get you a glamorous assistant with big tits
所以.... 我会给你找个胸大的助理
to take over from that frumpy old cow you've got at the moment.
换掉你现在那个土包子
You know, Mrs. fucking Doubtfire.
那个什么多德法尔女士
Danny, er... Jason gave me your breakfast show.
丹尼... 杰森把你的早间新闻给我播了
- Yeah.  - Is that true?
- 嗯  - 他说的是真的吗?
- Well...  - Twat.
- 是这样...  - 蠢货
Oh, my God.
天啊
Go! Go! Go!
快上! 快上!
Armed police!
武装警察!
Armed police! Everybody stay down!
武装警察! 所有人趴下!
- Stay down! Don't move! Don't move!  - Have you got any scissors?
- 蹲下! 别动!  - 你们有剪刀吗?
Have you got any scissors?
你们有剪刀吗?
Armed police! Armed police!
武装警察! 武装警察!
Studio's empty. Where's Farrell? Where's Partridge?
办公室里没人 法莱尔在哪里? 法莱尔在哪里?
# Roll out the barrel... #
# 滚啤酒桶... #
Get into position, get in front of that bus!
各就各位 站到车前!
We got three on a bus. Three on a bus. I want a green light on a sniper now.
车上有三个人 我需要一个狙击手
This cannot be happening.
不会吧
Jeez, Alan. Look at this. Quite alarming, isn't it?
天啊 阿兰 看 好大的场面 是吧?
Er... I think... I think we'll be fine.
呃... 我们不会有事的
Thanks for doing this, Alan. I wanted to stick it to Goredale one more time.
谢谢你 阿兰 我只是想在格尔戴尔传媒公司多待一会
I don't mind in the slightest, Pat. Goredale are tits.
派特 我自甘平庸 格尔戴尔总是焦点
Right, coppers, I've got nae tax, nae insurance and I'm not wearing a seatbelt.
警察们 我没有交税 没有交保险 也没系安全带
What are you going to do about it this time?
你们要把我怎么着?
- Start the car! Start the car!  - Let's go!
- 快开车! 快开车!  - 我们走!
帕屈吉来了
Right, let's give them some stick.
对 我们给他们点颜色瞧瞧
You're listening to Pat and Alan
你们正在收听的是帕特和阿兰带来的
with a message for the Goredale Medias of this world.
关于格尔戴尔传媒公司的报道
If you think you can take real DJs and turn them into radio robots,
如果你认为能用机器人代替真人主播
think again, because we're gonna get up in your face.
那你要好好想想了 因为我们要证明给你们看
Great.
是的
With a big fat slice of road show radio right here, right now.
此时此刻 我们要带给大家一场现场路演
The time is 1:27.
现在是下午1点27分
This is John Farnham and The Voice.
下面是约翰・法汉演唱的"我的声音"(澳大利亚摇滚歌王)
Today we're asking, why do people keep their eggs in the fridge?
今天的问题是 为什么人们要把鸡蛋放在冰箱里?
Once again, why do people insist on keeping their eggs in the fridge?
再说一遍 为什么人们非要把鸡蛋放在冰箱里?
And can a binman reasonably expect a Christmas tip
还有个问题 清洁工人如果拒绝收坏掉的烤面包机
when he has point-blank refused to dispose of a broken toaster?
那他还能不能拿到圣诞节奖金了?
- Good question!  - And that can be today's large question.
- 好问题!  - 那今天的提问就是它了
Large question.
提问时间到
Oh, and we have some travel news. There's slow-moving traffic on the A149.
现在播报交通信息 A149路段交通非常缓慢
That'll be due to wacky blokes on a big yellow bus.
这都是一辆大黄车里的怪叔叔闯的祸
It's competition time, and we 're playing pairs.
比赛开始啦 我们玩配对游戏
- Sid on line two. Black and...  - Decker.
- 超人二人组 百...  - 百得公司
- Spick and...  - Span.
- 一尘...  - 不染
- Hall and...  - Oates.
- 霍尔和...  - 奥兹
- Egg and...  - Bacon.
- 鸡蛋和...  - 培根
Oh, it was gammon!
噢 明明是腌猪腿!
Can I just say, I think Goredale are awful.
我想直接说出来 格尔戴尔烂透了
Yeah, they are bastards.
没错 一帮子混蛋
That's why I've washed my hands of them. You know what I say?
这就是我不干的原因 你懂我的意思吗?
I always say, "What doth it profit a man if he gain the whole world yet lose his soul?"
我常常说"如果失去了灵魂 就算赢了全世界 又有什么意义呢?"
And people seem to like that. They really do.
大家好像很认可我 真的是这样
# You're the voice, try and understand it #
# 你就是声音 试着去领悟 #
# Make a noise and make it clear #
# 说出来吧 大声喊出来 #
# Whoa, oh, oh, oh, oh-oh #
# 哇 噢 噢 噢 #
# Whoa-oh, oh, oh-oh, oh, oh! #
# 哇 噢 噢 噢! #
# We're not gonna sit in silence We're not gonna live with fear #
# 我们不会坐以待毙 我们毫无畏惧 #
# Whoa-oh, oh, oh, oh, oh-oh #
# 哇 噢 噢 噢 #
It looks like you've touched a nerve, Pat.
派特 你好像引起所有人的共鸣了
These are my listeners, Alan, ordinary working people.
他们是我的听众 阿兰 广大劳动人民
They're not working, it's the middle of the day.
现在是中午 他们不用上班
Unless they're on flexi-time.
除非是弹性上班制
Oh, look. I used to live in one of those after my divorce.
快看 我离婚那会 在那住过一阵子
TV, kitchen, very nice.
电视和厨房都很棒
Hey, people, I'm looking at a picture of Goredale Media.
嘿 伙计们 我在看格尔戴尔媒体的全家福
Honestly, look at that bunch of corporate mercenaries.
说实话 一帮子唯利是图的家伙
What's wrong with doing radio for the love of radio?
为什么不能为了纯粹的热爱去广播呢?
They would do anything for 30 pieces of silver.
为了半毛钱他们什么都愿干
You're listening to the Pat and Alan Show. Radio for the love of radio.
现在你们收听的是"帕特和阿兰秀" 因为爱 所以广播
Sponsored by Castro.
由卡斯特罗赞助播出
Just gonna use the loo.
我去下洗手间
- Alan?  - Hi.
- 阿兰?  - 嗨
Alan, I want to talk to you.
阿兰 我有话要和你说
Alan?
阿兰?
Oh, hi, Pat.
噢 嗨 派特
Alan, how did you even get in there?
阿兰 你怎么进去的?
Um... l just removed an aluminium panel. Slid straight in.
额... 我挪走了一块铝板 就滑进来了
- Er... textbook. It's good in there, isn't it?  - Your voice sounds funny.
- 看了下手册 这里还不错 对吧?  - 你声音听起来很搞笑
I think the conical shape of the toilet's turned
我想是马桶是环形的
it into a sort of a compact amphitheatre.
所以带点环绕音效
- It's weird.  - It is, Pat. It's bizarre.
- 好奇怪  - 没错 派特 非常古怪
It is and was a failed escape attempt, a
我想逃来着 可是失败了
sort of a Shitshank Redemption, if you will.
你可以这么看 有点像失败版的"肖申克救赎"
Ah. The Armitage Shank Redemption, eh?
阿兰的救赎 对吗?
Ha-ha-ha, ha-ha! I'm laughing like a drain and I'm in one.
哈哈哈 哈哈! 我笑声像管道 我自己也在水管里
Shake hands, Pat. Friends. Friends, Pat, friends.
握个手 派特 好朋友 派特是我的好朋友
Friends? I know what you did, you fucking snake.
朋友? 我知道你都做了什么 你这个老滑头
- "Just sack Pat."  - Huh?
- "解雇派特"  - 什么?
- You're as bad as the rest of them.  - Pat, be reasonable.
- 你和他们一样  - 派特 冷静点
Before you think of shooting anyone, just for a second think,
开枪之前 就稍微想想
what would drive a man to incarcerate himself in the septic tank? It's pathetic.
一个人是有多可悲 才会把自己塞进粪池呢?
- I'm not going to shoot you.  - Thank God for that. That's good news.
- 我不会杀了你  - 谢天谢地 这是个好消息
Sweet mother of God, no.
我的神啊 不要啊
Oh, angels and saints preserve us!
愿天使和圣徒保佑我们!
Dear God, let them be firm!
上帝啊 最好别拉稀!
Help!
救命啊!
Stop the bus!
停车!
- What's that?  - It's a septic tank. You can have it.
- 这是什么?  - 粪池 你可以拿去
Oh... not again!
噢... 要不要这样!
Damn gypsies tampered with the sights.
该死的吉普寨人 又在枪的准心上耍花样
Trust me, Susan.
相信我 苏珊
Ow! Jesus!
噢! 天啊!
Suspect is on Cromer...
疑犯在克罗默...
You're a fucking clown, Alan.
阿兰 你是个可怜虫
Ah. Hi, Pat.
啊 嗨 派特
I trusted you, Alan. I thought we were friends.
阿兰 我信任你 我以为我们是朋友
- But you let me down.  - Well, I...
- 可你背叛了我  - 我...
- You got me sacked.  - Over here! Pat!
- 你害我被开除  - 看这! 派特!
Look!
瞧!
Oh, shit!
糟糕!
What was that?
他在搞什么?
I think it was supposed to be some sort of distraction. Yeah.
打算转移你的注意力来着 没错
- Brave but pointless.  - Excuse me?
- 非常勇敢 可是毫无意义  - 怎么回事?
Oh, God, get back inside. Quick, now!
天啊 快进去 快点!
- We want to get down there.  - Do you mind? This is an armed stand-off.
- 我们想下去  - 你搞清点状况? 我们在火力对峙
- Where were we?  - I got you sacked.
- 说到哪了?  - 我害你开除
- Yeah, you let me down.  - Pat, listen to me.
- 是的 你背叛了我  - 派特 听我说
- I've got this.  - Pardon?
- 我可以处理  - 什么?
- I said, I've got this.  - How long is it going to go on for?
- 我说 我可以处理  - 你们打算搞多久?
- Shut up!  - He's telling you to shut up.
- 闭嘴!  - 他叫你闭嘴
- Calm down.  - Didn't get that.
- 冷静点  - 没听清
- Too close to your mouth.  - Calm down.
- 你离话筒太近了  - 冷静点
- It's too close to your mouth!  - Did you get that?
- 话筒离得太近了!  - 你没听见吗?
Did I get what?
听见什么?
She's saying, if you put your air rifles back, you won't be in too much trouble.
她说 如果你放下来复气枪 你就不会有麻烦
- This is a shotgun.  - This is an air rifle. That's a shotgun.
- 这是把猎枪  - 这是把气枪 那把才是真的
We'll leave you to it.
你们自己解决吧
I surrender.
我投降
Pat?
派特?
- I brought Molly to this pier.  - Happy times.
- 我过去带茉莉来过这个码头  - 美好时光
I scattered her ashes here.
我把她的骨灰洒在这
Ah.
啊
Buried at sea.
埋葬在大海里
Like Bin Laden.
和本・拉登一样
And now here we are.
现在我们也在这
The circle of life.
命运的轮回
Cirque du Soleil.
太阳马戏团
Turn your head away.
别看着我
Let's just calm down.
冷静点
- Pat, come on.  - Turn your head away.
- 派特 别这样  - 别看着我
- Pat, listen to me...  - Pat, you're scaring me.
- 派特 听我说...  - 派特 你吓坏我了
- I won't ask again.  - Pat, I need you to stay calm.
- 我不想再说第三次  - 派特 你冷静一点
Turn your head away.
别看着我
# Maybe I didn't love you, quite as often as I could have #
# 也许我对你的爱不够 常常忽略了你 #
What are you doing?
你在做什么?
# Maybe I didn't treat you, quite as good as I should have #
# 或许我待你不够好 没有尽自己本分 #
Stop it!
别唱了!
# And if I made you feel second best #
# 倘若我令你觉得自己不够重要 #
# Girl, I'm sorry I was blind #
# 宝贝 对不起 我太糊涂 #
# But you were always on my mind #
# 但你永远在我心中 #
# You were always on my mind #
# 你永远在我心中 #
- # Maybe I... #  - Pat, are you ready to...
- # 也许我... #  - 派特 你准备好...
Shut up, you dick!
闭嘴 该死的!
Pat, what are you doing?
派特 你在干什么?
I want to be with Molly.
我想和茉莉一起
What?
什么?
I want to be with Molly.
我想和茉莉一起
- Pat, don't do this.  - Pat, don't do this!
- 派特 别这样  - 派特 别干傻事!
Unbelievable.
不可思议
- I can't reach the trigger.  - Pat, come on.
- 我够不到扳机  - 派特 别这样
Would you do it for me?
你能帮我吗?
Yeah, course I will, mate.
是啊 当然 伙计
Course I will.
我当然会帮你
It's over, Pat.
都结束了 派特
No more hurting.
不会再有人受伤了
Ow!
噢!
Aaargh!
啊!
You fucking idiot!
你们这帮蠢货!
Shit.
该死的
- Stay with me, Alan. Stay with me.  - They've blown me to bits, Lynn.
- 别睡过去 阿兰 别睡过去  - 琳 他们把我炸碎了
I feel cold.
我觉得好冷
It's all right, Alan. God is with us.
没事的 阿兰 上帝与我们同在
We had some mad times, didn't we, Lynn?
琳 我们有过疯狂的时光 对吗?
There's some blood coming from my mouth, Lynn.
琳 我吐血了
- It's just spit.  - Is it? Oh, yeah.
- 口水而已  - 是吗? 没错
- Alan, I'm really sorry.  - It's all right, Pat.
- 阿兰 我很抱歉  - 没事 派特
- You've still got the gun!  - Aargh!
- 你还拿着枪!  - 啊!
Was I a good man, Lynn? Was I a kind man?
琳 我是个好人吗? 我是个善良的人吗?
Very kind.
你很善良
I remember when you were defrosting your freezer and you gave me all that bacon.
我还记得你给冰箱除霜 然后送给我一整块培根
I'm ready, Lynn.
我准备好了 琳
I think I'm ready.
我想我准备好了
Oh. Hello, Mister Seagull.
哦 你好 海鸥先生
Have you come to take my spirit away?
你是来带走我的灵魂吗?
Go, gull!
走吧 海鸥!
Gull... gull... gull.
海鸥... 海鸥... 海鸥
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 优兰达子 笑点滴 水果哥 Mabb 初见 咳嗽的小鱼
校对: 失眠影
What are you doing? I'm watching it fly off.
你在干什么? 我在看海鸥飞走呢
It's weird, Lynn. Yours will be the last face I ever see.
真奇怪 琳 你是我见过的最后一个人
- Oh, good.  - Hi there. You're gonna be OK.
- 噢 很好  - 嗨 听着 你会没事的
- I've been shot in the heart.  - Your heart's there. That's your shoulder.
- 我被射中心脏了  - 你的心脏在那儿 这是肩膀
No, that... that's my heart. Ow!
不 那... 那是我的心脏 噢!
- Can I have my job back now?  - Yeah, if you want.
- 我能回来工作吗?  - 是的 只要你愿意
# Maybe I didn't love you #
# 可能我对你的爱不够 #
How long have you been a paramedic?
你当医生多久了?
- About four years.  - Right.
- 差不多四年了  - 很好
And do you start in St John's Ambulance and then work your way up
你开始在圣约翰急救中心 然后慢慢被提拔上来
or are they separate organisations?
还是他们本来就是独立的部门?
- They're separate organisations.  - She can answer for herself, Lynn.
- 他们本来就是独立的部门  - 我想听她说呢 琳
- They are separate organisations.  - Right.
- 他们是独立的部门  - 好的
- Are you courting?  - Well...
- 你在拍拖吗?  - 好吧...
Not you, Lynn!
我不是问你 琳!
North Norfolk's best music mix.
北诺福克最棒的音乐电台
We've had a letter from Louise in Thetford,
我们有封来自塞特福德露易丝的信
who says, "I'm sick to the back teeth of people poking fun at garden gnomes."
信里写道 "人们一拿土地公公开玩笑 我就牙疼"
They may be small and strange-faced, but they
他们也许很矮 长得也有点奇怪
bring a lot of pleasure to a lot of people.
但他们会给人们带来很多欢乐
Now, that's a letter, once upon a time I would have found offensively dull.
瞧 很久以前的我很觉得这封信很冒犯人 很愚蠢
- Yeah.  - Not now.
- 是的  - 现在不会了
So maybe everything that happened has changed you.
也许发生的一切改变了你
I think I have changed a little bit.
我也觉得我变了一点点
Well, for my part, I was a bit worried about my head...
对我来说 我有点担心我的脑袋...
- Here we go.  - But um...
- 又来了  - 不过...
- I think I've got a handle on it now.  - Oh, yeah, that's a good joke.
- 我想我已经能应付了  - 噢 没错 这笑话还不赖
You've used that joke about three or four times now.
你现在每天要把这笑话讲好几遍
- I don't know if you're aware of that.  - I use it too much?
- 我不知道你意识到没有  - 我有一直讲吗?
I wouldn't say that. I just think we're in that area and... you know.
我可没这么说 我想我们已经到了... 你懂的
- What about the hat?  - Good for the bin, I reckon.
- 帽子怎样?  - 我觉得还是丢掉吧
- Lose it?  - Yeah.
- 丢掉?  - 是的
But I think, like you say, you're coming on leaps and bounds...
不过我认为 就像你说的 你要一直这么跳来跳去...
and I think, 12 months' time,
要不了一年吧
you'll probably have forgotten there ever was a siege.
估计你就忘了那次人质事件了
- What siege?  - Er... exactly. That's good.
- 什么人质事件?  - 我就说嘛 很好
- You haven't really forgotten?  - No.
- 你真的都不记得了?  - 没印象
OK, time now for our weekly phone call with incarcerated DJ Pat Farrell.
好了 又到了我们每周一次的连线主播派特・法莱尔的时间了
- It's...  - # Ring-ring from Sing-Sing! #
- 是...  - # 来自监狱的电话! #
Hello, Pat. Wagwan!
嗨 派特 你好吗!
Er... Hi, Alan.
呃... 嗨 阿兰
OK, this week's question comes from Sue, a dental hygienist from Grantham.
好的 这周的问题来自住在格兰瑟姆的牙医苏
She asks, "Prison time is often referred to as porridge"
她问你 "监狱时间一般指喝粥时间"
but do they actually serve porridge, and if so, is it compulsory?"
他们真的会供应粥吗 如果真有 是不是强制得喝?"
Yeah, they serve porridge but you can have other things.
是的 他们会供应粥 但你也可以吃别的
Thanks, Pat. We'll have another question for you next week, until then...
谢谢 派特 下周我们会问你新的问题 在那之前...
# Keep your nose clean, boy. #
# 别惹麻烦 我的好孩子 #
派特・法莱尔连续五周出现在阿兰的栏目中 他现在每个月都给阿兰写封信 目前为止 只收到了一封回信
# It's number one all over heaven #
# 天堂里最棒的歌 #
琳・本菲尔德承认她出过些主意 不过她决定绝口不提 阿兰・帕屈吉也不再追究了
# The number one song all over heaven #
# 天堂里最棒的歌 #
# If you should die before you awake #
# 如果在你醒来前该死去 #
救急人员在搜寻麦克45分钟未果的情况下 终止救援 他至今下落不明
# If you should die while crossing the street #
# 你应该在过马路的时候死去 #
海狮合唱团成立于1979年 在全球售出了1500万张唱片
# The song that you'll hear, I guarantee #
# 我保证 你现在所听的歌 #
Colby, Philip? If you guys don't dig the sounds,
科比 飞利浦? 如果你们无所谓听什么
sling us your pod, I'll dock it.
把iPod给我 我来找点好听的
You won't like it.
你不会喜欢的
Guys, I dig a lot of stuff.
伙计们 我发现过很多好听的歌
A good beat's a good beat.
健康的心脏跳着健康的节奏
# All the wrong places #
# 错误的地方 #
Sorry, not listening to that.
抱歉 不听这个
# It's number one all over heaven #
# 天堂里最棒的歌 #
# The number one song all over heaven #
# The song filters down, down through the clouds #
# 歌声从云端漏下来 #
# It reaches the earth and winds all around #
# 到了地球 风将歌声传遍四面八方#
# And then it breaks up in millions of ways #
# 于是有了上万种不同的调调 #
# It goes la, la, la, la, la la, la la #
# 就像这样 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 #
# La, la, la la, la la, la la #
# 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 #
# La, la, la la, la la, la, la, la, la-la-la #
# Whoo, in cars it becomes a hit #
# 哇 成为车里的流行乐 #
For God's sake, if it's that important...
上帝啊 如果这真的很重要...
# Toe to toe #
# 面对面 #
# We all stand tall #
# 我们并肩而战 #
# Row by row #
# 一排排 #
# All eyes glow #
# 眼里光芒在闪烁 #
# Like a rabbit in the headlights #
# 好像车前灯里的兔子 #
# Get your head right #
# 找对方向 #
# Start a new life Shiver in the moonlight #
# 在午夜前开始新的生活 #
# You must embrace it cos if not you'll waste it #
# 你得把握机会 不要浪费 #
# You're looking for love in all the wrong places #
# 你不该在错误的地方寻找爱 #
# All the wrong places... #
# 错误的地方... #
Sorry, that is awful.
不好意思 太难听了
# The Number One Song in Heaven #
# 天堂里最棒的歌 #
# Or soft as a doubt #
# 声音甜美 #
# Lyrically weak, but the music's the thing #
# 词写得不好 不过曲子才是关键 #
# Gabriel plays it, God, how he plays it #
# 加百列在弹奏 多么优美 #
# Gabriel plays it, let's hear him play it #
# It's number one all over heaven #
# 天堂里最棒的歌 #
# The number one song all over heaven #
# The song filters down, down through the clouds #
# 歌声从云端里漏下来 #
# It reaches the earth and winds all around #
# 到了地球 风将歌声传遍四面八方 #
# And then it breaks up in millions of ways #
# 于是有了上万种调调 #
# It goes la, la, la, la, la la, la la #
# 像这样 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 #
# La, la, la la, la la, la la #
# 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 #
啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 #
# La, la, la la, la la, la, la, la, la-la-la #
# 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 #
# Whoo, in cars it becomes a hit #
# 哇 成了车里的流行乐 #
# And in your home it becomes advertisements #
# 成了家里的广告 #
# And in the streets it becomes children singing #
# 成了路上孩子们的小调 #
# Ooh, la, la, la, la, la #
# 噢 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 #
# Ooh, la, la, la, la, la... #